<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
<package name="lazcontrols">
<!--
===============================================================================
laznumedit
===============================================================================
-->
<module name="laznumedit">
<short>
Implements an edit control specialized for Integer values which can be 
displayed with a specific numeric base (radix).
</short>
<descr/>

<!-- unresolved external references -->
<element name="Classes"/>
<element name="SysUtils"/>
<element name="Math"/>
<element name="StdCtrls"/>
<element name="LCLType"/>
<element name="Controls"/>
<element name="Clipbrd"/>
<element name="StrUtils"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditBaseChangeEvent">
<short>
Specifies an event handler signalled when the numeric base (radix) for an 
Integer edit control is changed.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
TLazIntegerEditBaseChangeEvent is the type used for the OnBaseChange property 
in TLazIntegerEditGen and TLazIntegerEdit. It allows actions to be performed 
when the numeric base (radix) for an integer edit control is changed.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.OnBaseChange"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.OnBaseChange"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditBaseChangeEvent.ASender">
<short>
Control for the event notification.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditBaseChangeEvent.ACurrentBase">
<short>
Current numeric base for the notification.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditBaseChangeEvent.ANewBase">
<short>
New numeric base for the notification.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditBaseChangeEvent.APrefix">
<short>
Optional prefix for the new numeric base.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.T">
<short>
Generic type. makeskel generated it... so it is included here. It doesn't 
appear to be used at all.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen">
<short>
Defines the base class for an Integer edit control using a specified numeric 
base.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
TLazIntegerEditGen is the generic base class for an edit control which can 
display and edit a 64-bit integer value using a specified numeric base or 
radix. TLazIntegerEditGen is the ancestor for the TLazIntegerEdit type which 
specializes the ancestor for the TCustomEdit type.
</p>
<p>
TLazIntegerEditGen introduces properties which determine the appearance and 
editing behavior for the control, including: Value, MinValue, MaxValue, and 
DisplayBase.
</p>
<p>
Value contains the decimal (base-10) value for the control as an Int64 type. 
MinValue and MaxValue control the lower and upper limits for the value in the 
control. DisplayBase determines the numeric base (base-2, base-8, base-16, 
etc.) used to display and edit the text for for the control.
</p>
<p>
Changing the value in DisplayBase causes the Value to be converted to the 
specified numeric base and the control is updated. A prefix is displayed for 
some numeric base values like base-2 (binary), base-8 (octal) and base-16 
(hexadecimal). Other numeric base values do not use a prefix.
</p>
<p>
The edit control supports changing the numeric base using DisplayBase, or using 
key presses which force the radix to be changed. See ToggleBinKeys, 
ToggleOctKeys, ToggleHexKeys for more information.
</p>
<p>
Use the OnBasechange event handler to perform actions needed when DisplayBase is changed for the control.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit"/>
<link id="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit">TCustomEdit</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- protected -->
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.Min_limit">
<short>
Lower limit for the Int64 value in the control.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Max_limit"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MinValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.Max_limit">
<short>
Upper limit for the Int64 value in the control.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Min_limit"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MaxValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- private -->
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FAllowMinus"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FAllowPlus"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FOnBaseChange"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FDisplayBase"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FBinIndicator"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FHexIndicator"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FOctIndicator"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FSetBinKeys"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FSetDecimalKeys"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FSetHexKeys"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FSetOctKeys"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FToggleBinKeys"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FToggleHexKeys"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FToggleOctKeys"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FMinValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FMaxValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FCurrentBasePrefix"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FCurrentPrefix"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.FLastDecodeWasEmpty"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.GetCurrentValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.GetCurrentValue.Result"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.GetValid"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.GetValid.Result"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetBinIndicator"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetBinIndicator.AValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetDisplayBase"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetDisplayBase.AValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetHexIndicator"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetHexIndicator.AValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetMaxValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetMaxValue.AValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetMinValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetMinValue.AValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetOctIndicator"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetOctIndicator.AValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetSetDecimalKeys"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetSetDecimalKeys.AValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetValue.AValue"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.UpdateText"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.UpdateText.ANewText"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.UpdateText.AnAdjustPos"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.UpdateText.AnAdjustOffset"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.UpdateText.AWasEmpty"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.ReEncodeText"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.ReEncodeText.Result"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.ReEncodeText.ACheckLimit"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.ReEncodeText.ANewBase"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.ReEncodeText.ANewPrefix"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.DecodeText"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.DecodeText.Result"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.DecodeText.APrefix"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.DecodeText.AVal"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.DecodeText.ACheckLimit"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.EncodeText"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.EncodeText.Result"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.EncodeText.APrefix"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.EncodeText.AVal"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.EncodeText.APrefixOnly"/>

<!-- protected -->
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyDown">
<short>
Implements an alternate KeyDown method for the generic base class.
</short>
<descr>
<p>	
_KeyDown is an implementation of the KeyDown method specific to the generic 
base class. It allows an alternate implementation without use of the override 
directive - which is not allowed in the generic class.
</p>
<p>
Key contains the virtual key code examined in the method. Shift contains the 
Alt, Ctrl, Shift, or Meta modifiers for the virtual key code.
</p>
<p>
_KeyDown calls the KeyDown method in the ancestor class on entry to signal an 
assigned OnKeyDown event handler, or any control handlers using the 
chtOnKeyDown handler type.
</p>
<p>
_KeyDown ensures that the following key codes are applied to the Text for the 
edit control:
</p>
<ul>
<li>VK_BACK</li>
<li>VK_DELETE</li>
</ul>
<p>
For both key codes, a visible sign (+ or -) or prefix for the DisplayBase in 
use on the the control is preserved.
</p>
<p>
_KeyDown is called from the overridden KeyDown method in the TLazIntegerEdit 
descendant.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.KeyDown"/>
<link id="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.KeyDown">TWinControl.KeyDown</link>
<link id="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnKeyDown">TWinControl.OnKeyDown</link>
<link id="#lcl.controls.TControl.DoCallKeyEventHandler">TControl.DoCallKeyEventHandler</link>
<link id="#lcl.controls.TControlHandlerType">TControlHandlerType</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyDown.Key">
<short>
Virtual key code for the key down notification.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyDown.Shift">
<short>
Shift, Ctrl, Alt, or Meta modifier(s) for the key code.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress">
<short>
Implements an alternate KeyPress method used in the control.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
_KeyPress is an implementation of the KeyPress method specific to the generic 
base class. It allows an alternate implementation without use of the override 
directive - which is not allowed in the generic class.
</p>
<p>
Key contains the character examined in the method.
</p>
<p>
_KeyPress calls the KeyPress method in the ancestor class on entry to signal 
an assigned OnKeyPress event handler.
</p>
<p>
_KeyDown ensures that the value in Key is not one of the allowed control 
characters used in the control, including:
</p>
<ul>
<li>#8 (Backspace)</li>
<li>#9 (Tab)</li>
<li>^A (Line Feed)</li>
<li>^C (Carriage Return)</li>
<li>^Z (Undo)</li>
</ul>
<p>
No actions are performed in the method if Key contains one of these values.
</p>
<p>
_KeyPress ensures that other characters or control characters in Key are 
properly applied to the Text in the control, including:
</p>
<dl>
<dt>'-'</dt>
<dd>
Toggles the sign when AllowMinus is enabled, and re-selects the Text displayed 
for the control.
</dd>
<dt>'+'</dt>
<dd>
Toggles the sign when AllowPlus is enabled, and re-selects the Text displayed 
for the control.
</dd>
<dt>^X (Cut)</dt>
<dd>
Copies the selected text on the control to the clipboard and removes the 
selected text from the display value for the control.
</dd>
<dt>^V (Insert)</dt>
<dd>
Copies the contents of the clipboard, converts it to the DIsplayBase in use, 
and inserts the value into the Text for the control. If text is selected on 
the control, only the selected text is replaced.
</dd>
<dt>ToggleBinKeys</dt>
<dd>
If Key contains one of he values in ToggleBinKeys, DisplayBase is toggled 
between 2 (Binary) and 10 (Decimal).
</dd>
<dt>ToggleOctKeys</dt>
<dd>
If Key contains one of he values in ToggleOctKeys, DisplayBase is toggled 
between 8 (Octal) and 10 (Decimal).
</dd>
<dt>ToggleHexKeys</dt>
<dd>
If Key contains one of he values in ToggleHexKeys, DisplayBase is toggled 
between 16 (Hexadecimal) and 10 (Decimal).
</dd>
<dt>SetDecimalKeys</dt>
<dd>
If Key contains one of he values in SetDecimalKeys, DisplayBase is switched 
to  10 (Decimal).
</dd>
<dt>SetBinKeys</dt>
<dd>
If Key contains one of he values in SetBinKeys, DisplayBase is switched to 2 (
Binary).
</dd>
<dt>SetOctKeys</dt>
<dd>
If Key contains one of he values in SetOctKeys, DisplayBase is switched to 8 (
Octal).
</dd>
<dt>SetHexKeys</dt>
<dd>
If Key contains one of he values in SetHexKeys, DisplayBase is switched to 16 (
Hexadecimal).
</dd>
</dl>
<p>
Key is set to #0 if it is handled in the method.
</p>
<p>
_KeyPress is called from the overridden KeyPress method in the TLazIntegerEdit 
descendant.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.AllowMinus"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.AllowPlus"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleBinKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleHexKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleOctKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetBinKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetDecimalKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetOctKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetHexKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.CurrentValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.KeyPress"/>
<link id="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.KeyPress">TWinControl.KeyPress</link>
<link id="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnKeyPress">TWinControl.OnKeyPress</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress.Key">
<short>
Character value for the key press notification. Set to #0 when handled in the 
method.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._Utf8KeyPress">
<short>
Implements an alternate UTF8KeyPress method used in the control.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
_Utf8KeyPress is an implementation of the Utf8KeyPress method specific to the 
generic base class. It allows an alternate implementation without use of the 
override directive - which is not allowed in the generic class.
</p>
<p>
_Utf8KeyPress calls the Utf8KeyPress method from the ancestor class on entry 
to signal an assigned OnUtf8KeyPress event handler for the class instance. The 
handler inspects the value in UTF8Key to determine whether it can be applied 
to the control. Any bytes values in UTF8Key not handled in the ancestor method 
are discarded. Essentially, this limits the input value for the control to the 
single byte characters in the UTF-8 encoding.
</p>
<p>
_Utf8KeyPress is called from the UTF8KeyPress method in the TLazIntegerEdit 
descendant.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.UTF8KeyPress"/>
<link id="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnUTF8KeyPress">TCustomEdit.OnUTF8KeyPress</link>
<link id="#lcl.controls.TCustomEdit.OnUTF8KeyPress">TCustomEdit.OnUTF8KeyPress</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._Utf8KeyPress.UTF8Key">
<short>
UTF-8-encoded character value for the key press notification.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._InitializeWnd">
<short>
Implements an alternate InitializeWnd method used in the control.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._RealGetText">
<short>
Implements an alternate RealGetText method used to get the text for the 
control.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._RealGetText.Result">
<short>
Caption text displayed in the edit box for the control.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._FinalizeWnd">
<short>
Implements an alternate FinalizeWnd method used in the control.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._DoExit">
<short>
Implements an alternate DoExit method used in the control.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._EditingDone">
<short>
Implements an alternate EditingDone method used in the control.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen._Init">
<short>
Implements an initialization routine used for new instances of the control.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
_Init acts as a constructor for instances of the generic base class. It is 
called from the constructor in TLazIntegerEdit to ensure that default values 
are assigned to members, including:
</p>
<ul>
<li>MinValue (Low(Int64))</li>
<li>MaxValue (High(Int64))</li>
<li>DisplayBase (10)</li>
<li>BinIndicator ('%')</li>
<li>HexIndicator ('$')</li>
<li>OctIndicator ('&amp;')</li>
<li>SetDecimalKeys ('#')</li>
<li>ToggleBinKeys ('%')</li>
<li>ToggleHexKeys ('$x')</li>
<li>ToggleOctKeys ('&amp;)</li>
<li>AllowMinus (<b>True</b>)</li>
<li>AllowPlus (<b>True</b>)</li>
</ul>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MinValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MaxValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.BinIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.HexIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.OctIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetDecimalKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleBinKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleHexKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleOctKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.AllowMinus"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.AllowPlus"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.Create"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- public -->
<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value">
<short>
Value for the control as an Int64 type.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Value</var> is an <var>Int64</var> property which contains the decimal 
(base-10) value for the control. Changing the property value causes the 
display Text in the control to be updated and displayed. DisplayBase 
determines the numeric base (radix) for the converted control Value. An 
optional prefix is used for numeric base values in DisplayBase like base-2 
(binary), base-8 (octal), and base-16 (hexadecimal).
</p>
<p>
Use MinValue and MaxValue to set lower and upper limits for the control Value. 
Changing the Value property causes the new value to be normalized for the 
limits in MinValue and MaxValue; if the new value is not in the specified 
range, it is changed to the corresponding lower or upper limit.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MaxValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MinValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.BinIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.HexIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.OctIndicator"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.CurrentValue">
<short>
Value for the control before EditingDone is called or the control loses focus.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
CurrentValue is a read-only Int64 property which contains the control value 
while editing is active and before the control loses focus. The property value 
is derived by reading the Text in the edit box and converting it from the 
selected DisplayBase back to a decimal (base-10) value. If a handle has not 
been allocated for the control, the Value property is used instead.
</p>
<p>
Use Valid to determine if the edit box contains a valid value for the 
specified DisplayBase.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Valid"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.Text"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.Valid">
<short>
Indicates whether the value in the CurrentValue property is valid for the 
setting in DisplayBase.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Valid is a read-only Boolean property which indicates whether the text 
displayed on the control is a valid numeric value for the setting in 
DisplayBase. Valid converts the edit text to an Int64 value, and checks 
whether the value is within the limits specified in MinValue and MaxValue. 
This includes comparing the prefix in the edit text (if any) to the prefix 
needed for the DisplayBase setting.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.CurrentValue"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.MinValue">
<short>
Sets the lower limit for the Value property.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
MinValue is an Int64 property which specifies the smallest Base-10 (decimal) 
value allowed for the control. Changing the value in MinValue causes any 
existing text on the edit control to be converted back to decimal (if needed) 
and normalized to the limits specified in MinValue and MinValue.
</p>
<p>
The default value for the property is set in the _Init method to the value in 
the Min_Limit constant.
</p>
<p>
Use MaxValue to specify the largest Base-10 Value allowed for the control.
</p>
<p>
MinValue and MaxValue are used when the Value property is updated, and ensure 
that the limits for the control are applied to Value before the display text 
is converted / displayed for the specified DisplayBase.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MaxValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._Init"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Min_limit"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.MaxValue">
<short>
Sets the upper limit for the Value property.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
MaxValue is an Int64 property which specifies the largest Base-10 (decimal) 
value allowed for the control. Changing the value in MaxValue causes any 
existing text on the edit control to be converted back to decimal (if needed) 
and normalized to the limits specified in MinValue and MinValue.
</p>
<p>
The default value for the property is set in the _Init method to the value in 
the Max_Limit constant.
</p>
<p>
Use MinValue to specify the smallest Base-10 Value allowed for the control.
</p>
<p>
MinValue and MaxValue are used when the Value property is updated, and ensure 
that the limits for the control are applied to Value before the display text 
is converted / displayed for the specified DisplayBase.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MinValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._Init"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Min_limit"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase">
<short>
Contains the numeric base (radix) for the value displayed in the control.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
DisplayBase is an Integer property which contains the numeric base (or radix) 
for the value displayed and maintained in the edit control.
</p>
<p>
DisplayBase determines the number of digits needed to represent the base-n 
text displayed on the control, and controls the conversion performed to get 
the display value. The default value for the property is 10 and indicates that 
the control displays its Value using base-10 or decimal notation.
</p>
<p>
DisplayBase must be in the range 2..35; a value outside this range is 
normalized to the lower or upper limit. 
</p>
<p>
Changing the value for the property causes the OnBaseChange event handler to 
be signalled (when assigned) using the old and new values for the property and 
the optional prefix for the new numeric base (radix).
</p>
<p>
The Text for control is updated by converting Value to the specified radix and 
applying the prefix for the DisplayBase. See BinIndicator, OctIndicator, and 
HexIndicator for more information about common prefixes used for selected 
DisplayBase values.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.OnBaseChange"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.BinIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.HexIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.OctIndicator"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetDecimalKeys">
<short>
Contains the characters which cause the edit control to be displayed using the 
decimal (base-10) radix.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
SetDecimalKeys is a String property which contains the character(s) used to 
switch the edit controls to the decimal (base-10) radix when a key press is 
handled for the control. SetDecimals is used in the _KeyPress handler, and 
causes the DisplayBase property to be set to 10.
</p>
<p>
The default value for the property is '#' as assigned in the _Init method.
</p>
<remark>
Please note that SetDecimalKeys is not like the toggles in the ToggleBinKeys, 
ToggleOctKeys, and ToggleHexKeys properties. It does not toggle between 
base-10 and another radix value. It selects base-10 only.
</remark>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._Init"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleBinKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleOctKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleHexKeys"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.HexIndicator">
<short>
Contains the prefix displayed in the control when the value is displayed in 
hexadecimal representation (DisplayBase = 16).
</short>
<descr>
<p>
HexIndicator contains the prefix displayed in the edit control when 
DisplayBase is set to 16 for hexadecimal format. The default value for the 
property is '$' as assigned in the _Init method. Changing the value for the 
property causes the text displayed on the control to be converted and 
re-encoded when DisplayBase is 16.
</p>
<p>
Use BinIndicator or OctIndicator for the prefix used for base-2 and base-8 
respectively.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._Init"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.BinIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.OctIndicator"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetHexKeys">
<short>
Contains the character(s) which cause the edit control to be displayed using 
the hexadecimal (base-16) radix.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
A default value is not assigned for the property. The ToggleHexKeys property 
is used to toggle between Hexadecimal (base-16) and Decimal (base-10). When a 
value is assigned to ToggleHexKeys, those keys take precedence over the keys 
in SetHexKey. The value in SetHexKeys is used, when applicable, in the 
_KeyPress handler for the control.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleHexKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleHexKeys">
<short>
Contains key(s) which cause the DisplayBase to be toggled between decimal 
(base-10) and hexadecimal (base-16) display formats.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
ToggleHexKeys is a String property which contains one or more characters which 
cause the DisplayBase for the control to be toggled between decimal (base-10) 
and hexadecimal (base-16). The default value for the property is '$x' as 
assigned in the _Init method. If either of the keys is entered when the 
control has focus, the DisplayBase property is updated accordingly and the 
display Text for the control is updated to to reflect the numeric 
representation using the radix.
</p>
<p>
Values in ToggleHexKeys are used in the _KeyPress method when a key value is 
applied to the edit control.
</p>
<p>
Use ToggleBinKeys or ToggleOctKeys to specify the key characters which cause 
the control to toggle between Binary or Octal, and Decimal representations for 
the control Value.
</p>
<p>
Use SetDecimalKeys, SetBinKeys, SetOctKeys, or SetHexKeys to switch to a 
specific base-n representation rather than toggle between a base-n 
representation and decimal (base-10).
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleBinKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleOctKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetDecimalKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetBinKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetOctKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetHexKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.KeyPress"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.OctIndicator">
<short>
Contains the prefix displayed in the control when the value is displayed in 
octal representation (DisplayBase = 8).
</short>
<descr>
<p>
OctIndicator contains the prefix displayed in the edit control when 
DisplayBase is set to 8 for octal format. The default value for the 
property is '&amp;' as assigned in the _Init method. Changing the value for 
the property causes the text displayed on the control to be converted and 
re-encoded when DisplayBase is 8.
</p>
<p>
Use BinIndicator or HexIndicator for the prefix used for base-2 and base-16 
respectively.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._Init"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.BinIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.HexIndicator"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetOctKeys">
<short>
Contains the character(s) which cause the edit control to be displayed using 
the octal (base-8) radix.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
A default value is not assigned for the property. The ToggleOctKeys property 
is used to toggle between Hexadecimal (base-16) and Decimal (base-10). When a 
value is assigned to ToggleHexKeys, those keys take precedence over the keys 
in SetOctKeys. The value in SetOctKeys is used, when applicable, in the 
_KeyPress handler for the control.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleOctKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleOctKeys">
<short>
Contains key(s) which cause the DisplayBase to be toggled between decimal (10) 
and octal (8) display formats.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
ToggleOctKeys is a String property which contains one or more characters which 
cause the DisplayBase for the control to be toggled between decimal (base-10) 
and octal (base-8). The default value for the property is '&amp;' as 
assigned in the _Init method. If the key is entered when the control has 
focus, the DisplayBase property is updated accordingly and the display Text 
for the control is updated to to reflect the numeric representation using the 
radix.
</p>
<p>
Values in ToggleOctKeys are used in the _KeyPress method when a key value is 
applied to the edit control.
</p>
<p>
Use ToggleBinKeys or ToggleHexKeys to specify the key characters which cause 
the control to toggle between Binary or Hexadecimal, and Decimal 
representations for the control Value.
</p>
<p>
Use SetDecimalKeys, SetBinKeys, SetOctKeys, or SetHexKeys to switch to a 
specific base-n representation rather than toggle between a base-n 
representation and decimal (base-10).
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleBinKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleHexKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetDecimalKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetBinKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetOctKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetHexKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.KeyPress"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.BinIndicator">
<short>
Contains the prefix displayed in the control when the value is displayed in 
binary representation (DisplayBase = 2).
</short>
<descr>
<p>
BinIndicator contains the prefix displayed in the edit control when 
DisplayBase is set to 2 for octal format. The default value for the property 
is '%' as assigned in the _Init method. Changing the value for the property 
causes the text displayed on the control to be converted and re-encoded when 
DisplayBase is 2.
</p>
<p>
Use OctIndicator or HexIndicator for the prefix used for base-8 and base-16 
respectively.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._Init"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.OctIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.HexIndicator"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetBinKeys">
<short>
Contains the character(s) which cause the edit control to be displayed using 
the binary (base-2) radix.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
A default value is not assigned for the property. The ToggleBinKeys property 
is used to toggle between Binary (base-2) and Decimal (base-10). When a 
value is assigned to ToggleBinKeys, those keys take precedence over the keys 
in SetBinKeys. The value in SetBinKeys is used, when applicable, in the 
_KeyPress handler for the control.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleBinKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleBinKeys">
<short>
Contains key(s) which cause the DisplayBase to be toggled between decimal (10) 
and binary (2) display formats.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
ToggleBinKeys is a String property which contains one or more characters which 
cause the DisplayBase for the control to be toggled between decimal (base-10) 
and binary (base-2). The default value for the property is '%' as assigned in 
the _Init method. If the key is entered when the control has focus, the 
DisplayBase property is updated accordingly and the display Text for the 
control is updated to to reflect the numeric representation using the radix.
</p>
<p>
Values in ToggleBinKeys are used in the _KeyPress method when a key value is 
applied to the edit control.
</p>
<p>
Use ToggleOctKeys or ToggleHexKeys to specify the key characters which cause 
the control to toggle between Octal or Hexadecimal, and Decimal 
representations for the control Value.
</p>
<p>
Use SetDecimalKeys, SetBinKeys, SetOctKeys, or SetHexKeys to switch to a 
specific base-n representation rather than toggle between a base-n 
representation and decimal (base-10).
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleOctKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleHexKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetDecimalKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetBinKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetOctKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetHexKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.KeyPress"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.OnBaseChange">
<short>
Event handler signalled when the value in DisplayBase is changed.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
OnBaseChange allows the control to perform actions needed when the value for 
the DisplayBase property is changed. It is signalled (when assigned) after the 
value in DisplayBase has been updated but before the Text in control is 
converted and displayed using the new radix. It allows the application to 
override the new numeric base or radix and prefix in the event handler.
</p>
<p>
See TLazIntegerEditBaseChangeEvent for more information about the handler type 
and its arguments.
</p>
<p>
OnBaseChange is a public property in TLazIntegerEditGen, but it is published 
in the TLazIntegerEdit descendant.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.Text"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditBaseChangeEvent"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.OnBaseChange"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.AllowMinus">
<short>
Indicates whether the '-' key can be used to negate the control Value.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
AllowMinus is a Boolean property which enables or disables use of the '-' key 
to change the sign for the value in the control. When enabled, the 
CurrentValue for the control is negated when the '-' key is pressed. A second 
press of the key causes the CurrentValue to become positive. The default value 
for the AllowMinus property is <b>True</b>. AllowMinus does enable direct 
entry of the sign; it reverses its state.
</p>
<p>
When editing is completed in the control, or it loses focus, the CurrentValue 
for the control is validated using the MinValue and MaxValue properties. If 
MinValue is not set to a value less than 0 (zero), a negative Value cannot be 
stored for the control and it defaults to MinValue.
</p>
<p>
AllowMinus and AllowPlus are used when key press events are applied in the 
_KeyPress handler.
</p>
<p>
Use AllowPlus to enable or disable use of the '+' key to force the control 
Value to become positive.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.AllowPlus"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.CurrentValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MaxValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MinValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._EditingDone"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.AllowPlus">
<short>
Indicates whether the '+' key can be used to switch a negative control value 
to a positive one.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
AllowPlus is a Boolean property which enables or disables use of the '+' key 
to change the sign for the Value in the control to a positive one. When 
enabled, the CurrentValue for the control is negated when the '+' key is 
pressed. and the control value is negative. No actions are performed if the 
CurrentValue is already positive. AllowPlus does enable direct entry of the 
sign; it simply forces a positive sign for the value.
</p>
<p>
When editing is completed in the control, or it loses focus, the CurrentValue 
for the control is validated using the MinValue and MaxValue properties.
</p>
<p>
AllowMinus and AllowPlus are used when key press events are applied in the 
_KeyPress handler.
</p>
<p>
Use AllowMinus to enable or disable use of the '-' key to toggle the sign for 
the control Value.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.AllowMinus"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.CurrentValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MaxValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.MinValue"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._EditingDone"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<!--
Commented out in source code too.

<element name="TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayQWord">
<short/>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
 -->

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit">
<short>
Implements an edit control for Integer values displayed and maintained using a 
specified numeric base or radix.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
TLazIntegerEdit is a TLazIntegerEdit descendant which specializes the generic base class for the TCustomEdit type. It implements an edit control which can 
display and edit a 64-bit integer value using a specified numeric base or 
radix.
</p>
<p>
TLazIntegerEdit introduces properties which determine the appearance and 
editing behavior for the control, including: Value, MinValue, MaxValue, and 
DisplayBase.
</p>
<p>
Value contains the decimal (base-10) value for the control as an Int64 type. 
MinValue and MaxValue control the lower and upper limits for the value in the 
control. DisplayBase determines the numeric base (base-2, base-8, base-10, 
base-16, etc.) used to display and edit the text for for the control.
</p>
<p>
Changing the value in DisplayBase causes the Value to be converted to the 
specified numeric base and the control is updated. A prefix is displayed for 
some numeric base values like base-2 (binary), base-8 (octal) and base-16 
(hexadecimal). Other numeric base values do not use a prefix.
</p>
<p>
The edit control supports changing the numeric base using DisplayBase, or using 
key presses which force the radix to be changed. See ToggleBinKeys, 
ToggleOctKeys, ToggleHexKeys for more information.
</p>
<p>
Use the OnBasechange event handler to perform actions needed when DisplayBase is changed for the control.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen"/>
<link id="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit">TCustomEdit</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- protected -->
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.KeyDown">
<short>  
Handles key down events for the control.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
KeyDown is an overridden method in TLazIntegerEdit. It ensures that key down 
events which affect the current selection in the control are properly applied.
</p>
<p>
KeyDown calls the alternate handler in the ancestor class (_KeyDown) to signal 
assigned OnKeyDown event handler attached to the control. It updates the 
values in SelStart and SelLength as needed when VK_BACK or VK_DELETE key down 
events are received and applied to the edit box.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyDown"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.KeyDown.Key">
<short>
Virtual key code for the key down event.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.KeyDown.Shift">
<short>
Shift, Ctrl, Alt, or Meta modifiers for the key down event.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.KeyPress">
<short>
Handles key press events for the control.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
KeyPress is an overridden method in TLazIntegerEdit. It calls the alternate 
_KeyPress handler in TLazIntegerEditGen to signal OnKeyPress (when assigned) 
and apply the specified character to the control. No actions are performed 
when ReadOnly is set to <b>True</b>.
</p>
<p>
KeyPress ensures that keys specific to the control or its DisplayBase are 
detected and applied to the control. This includes control characters like:
</p>
<ul>
<li>#8 (BS) (Backspace)</li>
<li>#9 (HT) (Tab)</li>
<li>#33 (^A) (Select All)</li>
<li>#35 (^C) (Copy)</li>
<li>#58 (^Z) (Undo)</li>
</ul>
<p>
Values in SelStart and SelLength are updated as needed when the Text in the 
control has been updated.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.KeyPress.Key">
<short>
Character for the key press notification.
</short>
</element>

<!-- WIP: Here -->
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Utf8KeyPress">
<short>
Handles UTF-8-encoded key press events for the control.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Ensures that multi-byte UTF-8 characters are ignored for the control.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Utf8KeyPress.UTF8Key">
<short>
UTF-8 character for the key press notification.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.RealGetText">
<short>
Gets the text displayed in the control.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Gets the value for the Text property using the handle for the control, or by 
converting Value to the required DisplayBase when a handle has not been 
assigned.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.Value"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.Text"/>
<link id="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.Text">TCustomEdit.Text</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.RealGetText.Result">
<short>
Value for the Text property.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.InitializeWnd">
<short>
Updates the value in Text when the window handle is created.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.FinalizeWnd">
<short>
Updates Value prior to freeing the window handle.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.DoExit">
<short>
Updates Value with the contents of Text when the control loses input focus.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.EditingDone">
<short>
Updates Value with the contents of Text when editing has been completed for the 
control.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<!-- 
Commented out in source code too.

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.DoEnter">
<short/>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
-->

<!-- public -->
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Create">
<short>
Constructor for the class instance.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Create is the overridden constructor for the class instance. It calls the 
_Init method in the base class to set the default values for members in the 
class instance. It calls the inherited constructor (in TCustomEdit) to set the 
default values for members in ancestor class.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Create.AOwner">
<short>
Owner of the class instance.
</short>
</element>

<!-- published -->
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Value" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.Value"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.MinValue" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.MinValue"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.MaxValue" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.MaxValue"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.DisplayBase" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.DisplayBase"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.SetDecimalKeys" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.SetDecimalKeys"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.HexIndicator">
<short>
Contains the prefix displayed in the control when the value is displayed in hexadecimal format (DisplayBase = 16).
</short>
<descr>
<p>
HexIndicator contains the prefix displayed in the edit control when 
DisplayBase is set to 16 for hexadecimal format. The default value for the 
property is '$' as assigned in the _Init method in the base class. Changing 
the value for the property causes the text displayed on the control to be 
converted and re-encoded when DisplayBase is 16.
</p>
<p>
Use BinIndicator or OctIndicator for the prefix used for base-2 and base-8 
respectively.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.BinIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.OctIndicator"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.Create"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._Init"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.SetHexKeys">
<short>
Contains the character(s) which cause the edit control to be displayed using 
the hexadecimal (base-16) radix.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
A default value is not assigned for the property. The ToggleHexKeys property 
is used to toggle between Hexadecimal (base-16) and Decimal (base-10) 
instead. When a value is assigned to ToggleHexKeys, those keys take precedence 
over the keys in SetHexKey. The value is used, when applicable, in the 
_KeyPress handler for the control.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.ToggleHexKeys"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEdit.DisplayBase"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen._KeyPress"/>
<link id="TLazIntegerEditGen.SetHexKeys"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- topics linked to the generic base class -->
<!-- 
	TODO: Replace with actual content. 
		FPDoc will not link to the topics in the generic base class. 
		It says the ancestor is TObject and not TCustomEdit, so the 
		links are ignored during doc generation.
-->
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.ToggleHexKeys" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleHexKeys"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OctIndicator" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.OctIndicator"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.SetOctKeys" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.SetOctKeys"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.ToggleOctKeys" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleOctKeys"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.BinIndicator" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.BinIndicator"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.SetBinKeys" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.SetBinKeys"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.ToggleBinKeys" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.ToggleBinKeys"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnBaseChange" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.OnBaseChange"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.AllowMinus" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.AllowMinus"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.AllowPlus" 
	link="#lazcontrols.laznumedit.TLazIntegerEditGen.AllowPlus"/>

<!-- topics linked to inherited topics -->
<!-- public -->
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.AutoSelected" 
	link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.AutoSelected"/>

<!-- published -->
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Align" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Align"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Alignment" 
	link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.Alignment"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Anchors" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Anchors"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.AutoSize" 
	link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.AutoSize"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.AutoSelect" 
	link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.AutoSelect"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.BidiMode" 
	link="#lcl.controls.TControl.BidiMode"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.BorderSpacing" 
	link="#lcl.controls.TControl.BorderSpacing"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.BorderStyle" 
	link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.BorderStyle"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.CharCase" 
	link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.CharCase"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Color" 
	link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Color"/>

<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Constraints" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Constraints"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.DoubleBuffered" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.DoubleBuffered"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.DragCursor" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.DragCursor"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.DragKind" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.DragKind"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.DragMode" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.DragMode"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.EchoMode" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.EchoMode"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Enabled" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Enabled"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Font" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Font"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.HideSelection" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.HideSelection"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.MaxLength" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.MaxLength"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.NumbersOnly" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.NumbersOnly"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.ParentBidiMode" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.ParentBidiMode"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.ParentColor" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.ParentColor"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.ParentDoubleBuffered" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.ParentDoubleBuffered"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.ParentFont" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.ParentFont"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.ParentShowHint" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.ParentShowHint"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.PasswordChar" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.PasswordChar"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.PopupMenu" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.PopupMenu"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.ReadOnly" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.ReadOnly"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.ShowHint" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.ShowHint"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.TabStop" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.TabStop"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.TabOrder" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.TabOrder"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Text" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.Text"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.TextHint" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.TextHint"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.Visible" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Visible"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnChange" link="#lcl.stdctrls.TCustomEdit.OnChange"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnChangeBounds" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnChangeBounds"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnClick" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnClick"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnContextPopup" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnContextPopup"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnDblClick" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnDblClick"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnDragDrop" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnDragDrop"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnDragOver" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnDragOver"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnEditingDone" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnEditingDone"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnEndDrag" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnEndDrag"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnEnter" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnEnter"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnExit" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnExit"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnKeyDown" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnKeyDown"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnKeyPress" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnKeyPress"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnKeyUp" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnKeyUp"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnMouseDown" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseDown"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnMouseEnter" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseEnter"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnMouseLeave" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseLeave"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnMouseMove" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseMove"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnMouseUp" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseUp"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnMouseWheel" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseWheel"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnMouseWheelDown" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseWheelDown"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnMouseWheelUp" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseWheelUp"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnResize" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnResize"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnStartDrag" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnStartDrag"/>
<element name="TLazIntegerEdit.OnUTF8KeyPress" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnUTF8KeyPress"/>

<element name="Str2QWord">
<short>
Converts the specified string to a QWord value using the specified numeric base.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="Str2QWord.Result">
<short>
Value for the specified string as a QWord type.
</short>
</element>
<element name="Str2QWord.S">
<short>
String with the value converted in the routine.
</short>
</element>
<element name="Str2QWord.Base">
<short>
Numeric base (or radix) for the QWord value in the result.
</short>
</element>

<element name="QWord2Str">
<short>
Converts a QWord value using the specified numeric base to its string 
representation.
</short>  
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="QWord2Str.Result">
<short>
String representation for the converted numeric value.
</short>
</element>
<element name="QWord2Str.N">
<short>
QWord value converted to a string in the routine.
</short>
</element>
<element name="QWord2Str.Base">
<short>
Numeric base (or radix) for the specified QWord value.
</short>
</element>

</module>
<!-- laznumedit -->

</package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
