<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions><package name="TAChartLazarusPkg"><module name="TAChartLiveView"><element name="TChartLiveView"><short><var>TChartLiveView</var> is a component optimized for displaying a long array of incoming data in a viewport with only the most recent data while older data are flowing to the left out of the vewport.</short><descr>The viewport is updated whenever the full extent of the associated chart changes. However, when property <var>Active</var> is set to <var>false</var> the viewport is fixed -- this is a setting which allows the user to review older data, or change the extent while still new data are coming at the same time.
</descr>
      </element><element name="TChartLiveView.Chart"><short>Chart on which the LiveView operates</short>
      </element><element name="TChartLiveView.ViewportSize"><short>Width of the visible viewport on the x axis, in graph units</short><descr>If set to 0, the width of the current <var>LogicalExtent</var> is used instead.
</descr>
      </element><element name="TChartLiveView.Active"><short>Allows to turn the scrolling controlled by the component ON and OFF.</short>
      </element><element name="TChartLiveView.ExtentY"><short>Mode determining how the vertical y axis is displayed in the scrolling viewport</short>
      <descr><p><var>lveAuto</var>: adjusts the height to the visible data range automatically. This works also when the chart contains several y axes. Ranges assigned to the axes (by setting <var>axis.Range.Min</var> and <var>axis.Range.UseMin</var>, and/or <var>axis.Range.Max</var> and <var>axis.Range.UseMax</var>) are respected (as long as data points are within this range).
</p><p><var>lveFull</var>: freezes the height to the full extent of the chart.</p><p><var>lveLogical</var>: freezes the height to the logical extent of the chart.</p>
        </descr>
      </element><element name="TChartLiveView.Create"><short>Constructor of the <var>TChartLiveView</var>
        </short>
      </element><element name="TChartLiveView.Destroy"><short>Destructor of the <var>TChartLiveView</var>
        </short>
      </element>
    </module>
  </package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
