<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
  <package name="TAChartLazarusPkg">
    <module name="TAMath"><element name="EnsureOrder"><short>If <var>A</var> is greater than <var>B</var> then both numbers are exchanged to make sure that <var>A</var> is never greater than <var>B</var>.</short>
      </element><element name="ExpandRange"><short>Expands the interval between <var>ALo</var> and <var>AHi</var> by subtracting <var>ACoeff</var> from <var>ALo</var> and adding it to <var>AHi</var>
        </short>
      </element><element name="SafeEqual"><short>Checks whether <var>A</var> is equal to <var>B</var> in a way which does not crash when one of the arguments is <var>NaN</var> ("not a number").</short>
      </element>
    <element name="SafeMin"><short>Returns the minimum of the numbers <var>A</var> and <var>B</var>. Does not crash when one of the values is <var>NaN</var> (Not a Number).</short>
      </element><element name="SafeInRange"><short>Returns <var>true</var> when <var>AValue</var> is within or at the bounds of the interval between <var>ABound1</var> and <var>ABound2</var>
        </short>
      </element><element name="SafeInRangeWithBounds"><short>Returns <var>true</var> when <var>AValue</var> is within or at the bounds of the interval between <var>ABound1</var> and <var>ABound2</var>
        </short><descr>Whether <var>AValue</var> is at the bounds of the interval is allowed within the specified tolerance <var>AEpsilon</var> where the default <var>AEpsilon=0</var> is interpreted as a <var>1E-12</var> fraction of the interval length.
</descr>
      </element><element name="SafeNan"><short>Returns a value of <var>NaN</var> ("not a number") with range checking and overflow checking turned off.</short>
      </element><element name="Ulps"><short>Converts the double-precision value <var>AX</var> to an integer 2's complement representation.</short><descr>The difference between resulting integers can be interpreted as distance in ulps.
</descr>
      </element><element name="SafeInfinity"><short>Returns a value of the special number <var>Infinity</var> with range checking and overflow checking turned off.</short>
      </element>
    <element name="InRangeUlps"><short>Returns <var>true</var> when <var>AX</var> is within or at the bounds of the interval between <var>ALo</var> and <var>AHi</var>
        </short><descr>The double-precision parameters are converted to an integer 2's complement representation.
The comparison is made with a tolerance of <var>AMaxUlps</var>.
</descr>
      </element><element name="CumulNormDistr"><short>Calculates the value of the <b>cumulative normal distribution</b> for the argument <var>AX</var>
        </short>
      </element><element name="InvCumulNormDistr"><short>Calculates the value of the <b>inverse cumulative normal distribution</b> for the argument <var>AX</var>
        </short>
      </element>
    </module>
  </package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
