<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions><package name="SynEdit"><module name="SynHighlighterXML">
<element name="TSynXMLSyn.CommentAttri">
<short>Highlight info for comments in XML</short>
<descr>Color and style to be used for comments.

This does not include the comment-marker &lt;!-- and --&gt;. Those are symbols, but can have their own attributes.
</descr>
<seealso>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.CommentSymbolAttri">CommentSymbolAttri</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TSynXMLSyn.CommentSymbolAttri">
<short>Highlight info for comment markers (symbols) in XML</short>
<descr>Color and style to be used for the symbols starting and ending a comment. &lt;!-- and --&gt;

Those markers are highlighted as normal symbols. But if any property in this <var>CommentSymbolAttri</var> is set, then the colors from this attribute will be used.
</descr>
<seealso>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.SymbolAttri">SymbolAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.CommentAttri">CommentAttri</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TSynXMLSyn.NamespaceColonAttri">
<short>Overlay Highlight info for colon separator in names with namespace</short>
<descr>If an Element or Attribute has a namespace this can be used to add extra highlight to the separating colon.
</descr>
<seealso>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.ElementAttri">ElementAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.AttributeAttri">AttributeAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.NamespaceDefinitionAttri">NamespaceDefinitionAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.fNamespacePrefixAttri">fNamespacePrefixAttri</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TSynXMLSyn.fNamespacePrefixAttri">
<short>Overlay Highlight info for the namespace part of an identifier</short>
<descr>If an Element or Attribute has a namespace this can be used to add extra highlight to the leading namespace part.
</descr>
<seealso>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.ElementAttri">ElementAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.AttributeAttri">AttributeAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.NamespaceDefinitionAttri">NamespaceDefinitionAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.NamespaceColonAttri">NamespaceColonAttri</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TSynXMLSyn.NamespaceDefinitionAttri">
<short>Overlay Highlight info for the namespace part of an identifier</short>
<descr>If a namespace is defined using <var>xmlns</var> this can add extra highlight to the namespace part.
</descr>
<seealso>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.AttributeAttri">AttributeAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.fNamespacePrefixAttri">fNamespacePrefixAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.NamespaceColonAttri">NamespaceColonAttri</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TSynXMLSyn.ProcessingInstructionSymbolAttri">
<short>Highlight info for processing instruction markers (symbols) &lt;? and ?&gt; in XML</short>
<descr>Color and style to be used for the symbols starting and ending a processing instruction. &lt;? and ?&gt;

Those markers are highlighted as normal symbols. But if any property in this <var>ProcessingInstructionSymbolAttri</var> is set, then the colors from this attribute will be used.
</descr>
<seealso>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.SymbolAttri">SymbolAttri</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TSynXMLSyn.ProcessingInstructionAttri">
<short>Overlay highlight info for entire processing instruction in XML</short>
<descr>Additional Color and style to be used for entire processing instruction. Between and including &lt;? and ?&gt;

The settings from this Attribute can overlay other attributes that apply to different parts of such an instruction.
They can replace them by priority, or merge using an Alpha channel.
</descr>
</element>
<element name="TSynXMLSyn.SymbolAttri">
<short>Highlight info for symbols in XML</short>
<descr>Color and style to be used for symbols. E.g. &lt;&gt;!?/=" and combinations of those.

Some symbols may have their own Attributes. They may use this setting as a fallback, if they have no setting at all. That is "fallback" is not per color/style, but for the entire TSynHighlighterAttribute (if the alternative has no single property set).
</descr>
<seealso>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.CommentSymbolAttri">CommentSymbolAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.ProcessingInstructionSymbolAttri">ProcessingInstructionSymbolAttri</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TSynXMLSyn.QuotesUseAttribValueAttri">
<short>Highlight quotes with the attributes for <var>AttributeValueAttri</var> instead of <var>SymbolAttry</var> </short>
<descr>Quotes around xml-attribute values are by default highlighted as Symbols.
If this option is set, the use the same highlight as the attribute value.
</descr>
<seealso>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.SymbolAttri">SymbolAttri</link>
  <link id="TSynXMLSyn.AttributeValueAttri">AttributeValueAttri</link>
</seealso>
</element>
</module></package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
