<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
  <package name="lcl">
    <!--
    ====================================================================
      AsyncProcess
    ====================================================================
    -->
    <module name="AsyncProcess">
      <short>
        Implements a process with asynchronous event notifications
      </short>
      <descr>
        <p>
          <file>asyncprocess.pp</file> implements a process with asynchronous event notifications for data availability and process termination. The following components are added to the Lazarus IDE component palette:
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>System</b> Tab
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>TAsyncProcess</li>
        </ul>
      </descr>

      <!-- unresolved  references -->
      <element name="Classes"/>
      <element name="Process"/>
      <element name="FileUtil"/>
      <element name="UTF8Process"/>
      <element name="InterfaceBase"/>
      <element name="LCLIntf"/>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess">
        <short>
          Implements a process with asynchronous notifications for data and termination
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TAsyncProcess</var> is a <var>TProcessUTF8</var> descendant which implements support for asynchronous notifications when data is available for the process. Internally, TAsyncProcess uses pipe and process handlers to detect when data is written to the <var>Output</var> handle, and when the process is terminated. TAsyncProcess provides <var>OnReadData</var> and <var>OnTerminate</var> event handlers signalled for the corresponding asynchronous notifications.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.OnReadData"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.OnTerminate"/>
          <link id="#lazutils.utf8process.TProcessUTF8">TProcessUTF8</link>
          <link id="#fcl.process.TProcess.Output">TProcess.Output</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.FPipeHandler"/>
      <element name="TAsyncProcess.FProcessHandler"/>
      <element name="TAsyncProcess.FOnReadData"/>
      <element name="TAsyncProcess.FOnTerminate"/>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.GetNumBytesAvailable">
        <short>
          Gets the value for the NumBytesAvailable property
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>GetNumBytesAvailable</var> is a <var>dword</var> function used to get the value for the <var>NumBytesAvailable</var> property. The return value contains the value from  <var>Output.NumBytesAvailable</var>, or 0 (zero) when <var>Options</var> does not include the value <var>poUsePipes</var>.
          </p>
          <p>
            Use <var>NumBytesAvailable</var> to access the value for the property.
          </p>
          <p>
            Use <var>Options</var> to specify the process options enabled for the class instance.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.NumBytesAvailable"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.GetNumBytesAvailable"/>
          <link id="#fcl.process.TProcess.Options">TProcess.Options</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TAsyncProcess.GetNumBytesAvailable.Result">
        <short>Value for the property</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.HandlePipeInput">
        <short>
          Implements asynchronous notifications during execution of the process
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>HandlePipeInput</var> is a procedure which implements support for asynchronous  notifications which occur during execution of the process. HandlePipeInput is assigned using <var>AddPipeEventHandler</var> when <var>Execute</var> is called.
          </p>
          <p>
            HandlePipeInput examines values in <var>AReasons</var> to determine the action for the notification. When AReasons includes the value <var>prBroken</var>, the pipe has been closed and <var>UnhookPipeHandle</var> is called. When <var>prDataAvailable</var> is included in AReasons, the <var>OnReadData</var> event handler is signalled (when assigned).
          </p>
          <p>
            Use <var>OnReadData</var> to respond to arrival of data on the handle for the process. Use <var>NumBytesAvailable</var> is determine the number of bytes available.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.OnReadData"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.NumBytesAvailable"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TAsyncProcess.HandlePipeInput.AData">
        <short>Data available on the input handle</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TAsyncProcess.HandlePipeInput.AReasons">
        <short>Reason the data was written for the handler</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.HandleProcessTermination">
        <short>
          Performs actions needed when the process is terminated
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>HandleProcessTermination</var> is a procedure which performs actions needed when the process is terminated. HandleProcessTermination is assigned using <var>AddProcessEventHandler</var> when <var>Execute</var> is called.
          </p>
          <p>
            HandleProcessTermination calls <var>UnhookProcessHandle</var> and <var>UnhookPipeHandle</var> to release the handlers in the class instance. HandleProcessTermination signals the <var>OnTerminate</var> event handler when it has been assigned.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.Execute"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.UnhookProcessHandle"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.UnhookPipeHandle"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.OnTerminate"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TAsyncProcess.HandleProcessTermination.AData">
        <short>Data for the process notification</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TAsyncProcess.HandleProcessTermination.AReason">
        <short>Reason(s) for the process notification</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TAsyncProcess.HandleProcessTermination.AInfo">
        <short>Process exit code</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.UnhookPipeHandle">
        <short>
          Removes the pipe handler assigned for the process
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>UnhookPipeHandle</var> is a procedure used to remove the pipe handler assigned for the process in the <var>Execute</var> method. UnhookPipeHandle calls <var>RemovePipeEventHandler</var> when a pipe handler has been assigned.
          </p>
          <p>
            <var>UnhookPipeHandle</var> is called from the <var>Destroy</var> method, and from <var>HandlePipeInput</var> when the <var>prBroken</var> flag is found in the parameters passed to the method.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.Execute"/>
          <link id="#lcl.interfacebase.TPipeReason">TPipeReason</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.UnhookProcessHandle">
        <short>
          Removes the process handler assigned for the process
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>UnhookProcessHandle</var> is a procedure used to remove the process handler assigned for the process in the <var>Execute</var> method. UnhookProcessHandle calls <var>RemoveProcessEventHandler</var> when a process handler has been assigned.
          </p>
          <p>
            <var>UnhookProcessHandle</var> is called from the <var>HandleProcessTermination</var> and <var>Destroy</var> methods.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.Execute"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.HandleProcessTermination"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.Destroy"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.Execute">
        <short>
          Executes the process
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Execute</var> is an overridden procedure used to execute the process. Execute calls the inherited Execute method on entry.
          </p>
          <p>
            Execute uses values in <var>Options</var> to determine if a process or a pipe handler is needed for the class instance. When Options includes the value <var>poUsePipes</var>, <var>AddPipeEventHandler</var> is called using <var>HandlePipeInput</var> as the pipe handler routine. Set the values in Options prior to calling the Execute method.
          </p>
          <p>
            Execute calls <var>AddProcessEventHandler</var> using <var>HandleProcessTermination</var> as the process handler routine.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.HandlePipeInput"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.HandleProcessTermination"/>
          <link id="#fcl.process.TProcess.Options">TProcess.Options</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.Destroy">
        <short>
          Destructor for the class instance
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Destroy</var> is the overridden destructor  for the class instance. Destroy calls <var>UnhookProcessHandle</var> and <var>UnhookPipeHandle</var> to remove the handler(s) for the class instance. Destroy calls the inherited method to free resources allocated in the class instance and perform free notifications.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.UnhookProcessHandle"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.UnhookPipeHandle"/>
          <link id="#fcl.process.TProcess.Destroy">TProcess.Destroy</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.NumBytesAvailable">
        <short>
          Number of output bytes available from the process
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>NumBytesAvailable</var> is a read-only <var>dword</var> property that indicates the number of bytes available on the <var>Output</var> handle for the process. <var>GetNumBytesAvailable</var> is the read access specifier for the property value. NumBytesAvailable contains the value in Output.NumBytesAvailable, or 0 (zero) when <var>Options</var> does not contain the value <var>poUsePipes</var>.
          </p>
          <p>
            Set the values for the <var>Options</var> property prior to calling <var>Execute</var>.
          </p>
          <p>
            Use <var>OnReadData</var> to respond to the process notification signalled when data is available.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.Execute"/>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.OnReadData"/>
          <link id="#fcl.process.TProcess.Options">TProcess.Options</link>
          <link id="#fcl.process.TProcess.Output">TProcess.Output</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.OnReadData">
        <short>
          Event handler signalled when output data is available for the process
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>OnReadData</var> is a <var>TNotifyEvent</var> property that implements the event handler signalled when data is available for the process. Applications should assign a procedure to the event handler that responds to the pipe notification. The procedure must handle all data available on the <var>Output</var> handle up to the number of bytes in <var>NumBytesAvailable</var>. All available data must be handled, or the procedure will be called repeatedly until no more data is available.
          </p>
          <p>
            OnReadData is signalled (when assigned) from the <var>HandlePipeInput</var> method when the <var>prDataAvailable</var> flag is found in the parameters passed to the method.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.NumBytesAvailable"/>
          <link id="#lcl.interfacebase.TPipeReason">TPipeReason</link>
          <link id="#fcl.process.TProcess.Output">TProcess.Output</link>
          <link id="#rtl.classes.TNotifyEvent">TNotifyEvent</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TAsyncProcess.OnTerminate">
        <short>
          Event handler signalled when the process is terminated
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>OnTerminate</var> is a <var>TNotifyEvent</var> property that implements the event handler signalled when the process is terminated. Applications can assign a procedure to the event handler to perform actions needed when the process is terminated.
          </p>
          <p>
            OnTerminate is signalled (when assigned) from the <var>HandleProcessTermination</var> method, and occurs after the process and pipe handlers have been unhooked in the class instance.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TAsyncProcess.HandleProcessTermination"/>
          <link id="#rtl.classes.TNotifyEvent">TNotifyEvent</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="Register">
        <short>Registers components for use in the Lazarus IDE</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Register</var> is the procedure used to register components for use in the Lazarus IDE.
            The following components are added to the Lazarus IDE component palette:
          </p>
          <p>
            <b>System</b> Tab
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li>TAsyncProcess</li>
          </ul>
        </descr>
        <seealso/>
      </element>

    </module>
    <!-- AsyncProcess -->
  </package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
