<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
  <package name="lcl">
    <!--
    ====================================================================
      Calendar
    ====================================================================
    -->
    <module name="Calendar">
      <short>
        Classes and types used to implement TCalendar, a graphic control allowing selection of a date from a calendar display.
      </short>
      <descr>
        <p>
          <file>calendar.pp</file> contains classes and types used to implement <var>TCalendar</var>, a graphic control allowing selection of a date from a calendar display.
        </p>
        <p>
          The following components are added to the Lazarus IDE component palette:
        </p>
        <p>
          <b>Misc</b> Tab
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>TCalendar</li>
        </ul>
        <p>
          <file>Calendar.pp</file> is part of the LCL (Lazarus Component Library).
        </p>
      </descr>

      <!-- unresolved references -->
      <element name="LCLProc"/>
      <element name="Types"/>
      <element name="SysUtils"/>
      <element name="Classes"/>
      <element name="LCLType"/>
      <element name="LCLStrConsts"/>
      <element name="LMessages"/>
      <element name="Controls"/>
      <element name="LResources"/>
      <element name="Math"/>

      <element name="TDisplaySetting">
        <short>
          Enumerated type with values that control display settings in TCalendar.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TDisplaySetting</var> is an enumerated type with values that control display settings in <var>TCalendar</var>. Values from TDisplaySetting are stored in the <var>TDisplaySettings</var> type.
          </p>
          <remark>
            Use of a display setting requires it to also be implemented on the native calendar control for a platform / widgetset. Most of the values in TDisplaySetting are ignored for the Windows platform; only dsShowWeekNumbers has the desired effect.
          </remark>
          <remark>
            The value <var>dsStartMonday</var> has been removed in LCL version 2.2 or higher.
          </remark>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="DefaultDisplaySettings"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DisplaySettings"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TDisplaySetting.dsShowHeadings">
        <short>Displays a month/year heading.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TDisplaySetting.dsShowDayNames">
        <short>Displays day names.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TDisplaySetting.dsNoMonthChange">
        <short>Prevents changing the current month.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TDisplaySetting.dsShowWeekNumbers">
        <short>Displays week numbers.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TDisplaySettings">
        <short>Set type for TDisplaySetting values.</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TDisplaySettings</var> is a set type used to store enumerations values from TDisplaySetting. It is the type used for the <var>DisplaySettings</var> property in <var>TCustomCalendar</var>.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DisplaySettings"/>
          <link id="TDisplaySetting"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="DefaultDisplaySettings">
        <short>
          Default display settings used in TCalendar.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>DefaultDisplaySettings</var> is a constant with the default display settings used in <var>TCalendar</var>. It is used as the default value for the DisplaySettings property in TCustomCalendar / TCalendar.
          </p>
          <p>
            DefaultDisplaySettings contains the following TDisplaySetting enumeration values:
          </p>
          <dl>
            <dt>dsShowHeadings</dt>
            <dd>Displays the month/year heading.</dd>
            <dt>dsShowDayNames</dt>
            <dd>Displays day names.</dd>
          </dl>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DisplaySettings"/>
          <link id="TDisplaySettings"/>
          <link id="TDisplaySetting"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCalendarPart">
        <short>
           Indicates where a mouse click occurred in a calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TCalendarPart</var> is an enumerated type with values that indicate where a mouse click occurred in a calendar control. TCalendarPart is used to implement the TCustomCalendar.HitTest method.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.HitTest"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarPart.cpNoWhere">
        <short>Mouse click cannot be applied to the control; no handle available.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarPart.cpDate">
        <short>Mouse click occurred on a date in the calendar control.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarPart.cpWeekNumber">
        <short>Mouse click occurred on a week number in the calendar control.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarPart.cpTitle">
        <short>Mouse click occurred on a day heading in the calendar control.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarPart.cpTitleBtn">
        <short>Mouse click occurred on a navigation button in a calendar control.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarPart.cpTitleMonth">
        <short>
          Mouse click occurred on the month name heading in the calendar control.
        </short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarPart.cpTitleYear">
        <short>
          Mouse click occurred on the year number heading in the calendar control.
        </short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCalendarView">
        <short>
          Defines the view for a calendar.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TCalendarView</var> is an enumeration type with values that define the view for a calendar control. TCalendarView makes it possible to set the calendar view introduced in Windows Vista or later. In other widgetsets, as well as in older versions of Windows, a calendar has only a standard "month view" grid with days representing a month. TCalendarView is used to implement the TCustomCalendar.GetCalendarView method.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.GetCalendarView"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarView.cvMonth">
        <short>Grid has days for one month.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarView.cvYear">
        <short>Grid has months in one year.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarView.cvDecade">
        <short>Grid has years from one decade.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalendarView.cvCentury">
        <short>Grid has decades for one century.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCalDayOfWeek">
        <short>Represents days of the week used in TCalendar.</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TCalDayOfWeek</var> is an enumerated type with values which represent the day used as the first day of the week in <var>TCustomCalendar</var> and descendants.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.FirstDayOfWeek"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalDayOfWeek.dowMonday">
        <short>Represents Monday.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalDayOfWeek.dowTuesday">
        <short>Represents Tuesday.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalDayOfWeek.dowWednesday">
        <short>Represents Wednesday.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalDayOfWeek.dowThursday">
        <short>Represents Thursday.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalDayOfWeek.dowFriday">
        <short>Represents Friday.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalDayOfWeek.dowSaturday">
        <short>Represents Saturday.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalDayOfWeek.dowSunday">
        <short>Represents Sunday.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCalDayOfWeek.dowDefault">
        <short>
          Use the default day of the week setting for the platform for the first day of the week. Not compatible with the value used in Delphi (dowLocaleDefault).
        </short>
      </element>

      <element name="EInvalidDate">
        <short>
          Exception raised for an invalid date in the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>EInvalidDate</var> is an exception raised when a invalid date is selected in a calendar control.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.MinDate"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.MaxDate"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar">
        <short>
          Implements the base class for <var>TCalendar</var>.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TCustomCalendar</var> is the base class for <var>TCalendar</var>, a graphic control used to select a date value from the familiar monthly calendar layout. It includes Date and DateTime properties with the selected date as a String or a TDateTime value.
          </p>
          <p>
            TCustomCalendar acts as a wrapper for the native calendar control on a given platform. The range of dates allowed in a native calendar control varies by platform. Starting in LCL version 2.4, TCustomCalendar includes MinDate and MaxDate properties which can used to limit the dates displayed on the calendar to a specified minimum and maximum date. Setting Date or DateTime to a value outside the allowed range (when used) causes an EInvalidDate exception to be raised.
          </p>
          <p>
            Please note that MinDate and MaxDate are not supported on all platforms; they are not implemented for GTK2 and GTK3 because the native calendar control does not implement or enforce them.
          </p>
          <p>
            DisplaySettings can be used to control the visual layout and behavior for the calendar. This includes the first day of the week for the calendar layout as well as use of headings, days names, and week numbers.
          </p>
          <p>
            Use the OnChange, OnDayChanged, OnMonthChanged, and OnYearChanged event handlers to perform actions needed when the date or its component values have been modified on the calendar control.
          </p>
          <p>
            Changes made to properties in the control are applied to the widgetset class instance (the native calendar control) when its handle has been allocated.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCalendar"/>
          <link id="#lcl.controls.TWinControl">TWinControl</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- private -->
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.FDateAsString"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.FDate"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.FDisplaySettings"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.FOnChange"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.FDayChanged"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.FMonthChanged"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.FYearChanged"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.FPropsChanged"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.FLimitsChanged"/>

      <!-- private -->
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.CheckRange"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.CheckRange.ADate"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.CheckRange.AMinDate"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.CheckRange.AMaxDate"/>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetDateTime">
        <short>Gets the value for the DateTime property.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetDateTime.Result">
        <short>Value for the DateTime property.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetMaxDateStored"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetMaxDateStored.Result"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetMinDateStored"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetMinDateStored.Result"/>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetDateTime">
        <short>Sets the value for the DateTime property.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetDateTime.AValue">
        <short>New value for the DateTime property.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetProps">
        <short>Gets values for properties in the calendar control.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetMaxDate"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetMaxDate.AValue"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetMinDate"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetMinDate.AValue"/>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetProps">
        <short>Sets values for properties in the calendar control.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetDisplaySettings">
        <short>Gets the value for the DisplaySettings property.</short>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DisplaySettings"/>
          <link id="TDisplaySettings"/>
          <link id="TDisplaySetting"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetDisplaySettings.Result">
        <short>Value for the DisplaySettings property.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetDisplaySettings">
        <short>Sets the value for the DisplaySettings property.</short>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DisplaySettings"/>
          <link id="TDisplaySettings"/>
          <link id="TDisplaySetting"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetDisplaySettings.AValue">
        <short>New value for the DisplaySettings property.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetDate">
        <short>Gets the value for the Date property.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetDate.Result">
        <short>Value for the Date property.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetDate">
        <short>Sets the value for the Date property.</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetDate.AValue">
        <short>New value for the Date property.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetFirstDayOfWeek"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.SetFirstDayOfWeek.AValue"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.IsLimited"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.IsLimited.Result"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.ApplyLimits"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.RemoveLimits"/>

      <!-- protected -->
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.WSRegisterClass" link="#LCL.LCLClasses.TLCLComponent.WSRegisterClass"/>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.LMChanged">
        <short>
          Handles the LCL LM_CHANGED message received when the calendar control is updated.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>LMChanged</var> ensures that event handlers are signalled (when assigned) when the value in DateTime is updated for the calendar control is changed. It retrieves the new date value from the widgetset class instance, and compares it to the existing value in DateTime. DecodeDateTime is used to get the year, month, and day component values compared in the method. The new value for DateTime is stored prior to comparing the values.
          </p>
          <p>
            When the date or one of its component values has been changed, the corresponding event handlers are signalled (when assigned) in the following order:
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li>OnYearChanged</li>
            <li>OnMonthChanged</li>
            <li>OnDayChanged</li>
            <li>OnChange</li>
          </ul>
          <p>
            An application can assign object procedures to the event handlers to respond to the change notifications.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnYearChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnMonthChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnDayChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnChange"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.LMChanged.Message">
        <short>Message handled in the method.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.LMMonthChanged">
        <short>
          Handles the LCL LM_MONTHCHANGED message received when the month has been changed using the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            The message is posted as a callback from the widgetset class when the active month on the control is changed. It can occur when a new date is selected, or when the GUI is used to change the visible month on the control. <var>LMMonthChanged</var> ensures that event handlers are signalled (when assigned) when the month displayed on the calendar control is changed. The event handlers are signalled in the following order:
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li>OnMonthChanged</li>
            <li>OnChange</li>
          </ul>
          <p>
            An application can assign object procedures to the event handlers to respond to the change notifications.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnMonthChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnChange"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.LMMonthChanged.Message">
        <short>Message handled in the method.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.LMYearChanged">
        <short>
          Handles the LCL LM_YEARCHANGED message received when the year number has been changed on the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>LMYearChanged</var> handles the message posted as a callback from the widgetset class when the year number on the control is changed. The message occurs when the year number is changed as a result of using the navigation controls on the calendar. It signals the OnYearChanged and OnChange event handlers (when assigned).
          </p>
          <p>
            An application can assign object procedures to the event handlers to respond to the change notifications.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnYearChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnChange"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.LMYearChanged.Message">
        <short>Message handled in the method.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.LMDayChanged">
        <short>
          Handles the LCL LM_DAYCHANGED message received when the day number has been changed on the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>LMDayChanged</var> handles the message posted as a callback from the widgetset class when the day number on the control is changed. The message occurs when the day number is changed as a result of using the navigation keys on the calendar, or when a new day number is clicked with the mouse. It signals the OnDayChanged and OnChange event handlers (when assigned).
          </p>
          <p>
            An application can assign object procedures to the event handlers to respond to the change notifications.
          </p>          
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnDayChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnChange"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.LMDayChanged.Message">
        <short>Message handled in the method.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetControlClassDefaultSize">
        <short>
          Gets the default dimensions for a new instance of the control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>GetControlClassDefaultSize</var> is an overridden <var>TSize</var> function in <var>TCustomCalendar</var>, and re-implements the method from the ancestor class. It returns the default width and height for the control in the CX and CY members for the TSize instance. Width (CX) is set to 220 pixels. Height (CY) is set to 190 pixels.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="#lcl.controls.TControl.GetControlClassDefaultSize">TControl.GetControlClassDefaultSize</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.Loaded">
        <short>
          Performs actions when the component has finished loading during LCL component streaming.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Loaded</var> is an overridden method in <var>TCustomCalendar</var>, and calls the inherited method on entry. It ensures that property values in the class instance are posted to the widgetset class instance when its handle has been allocated. At run-time, the following properties are updated in the widget instance:
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li>DateTime</li>
            <li>DisplaySettings</li>
            <li>FirstDayOfWeek</li>
            <li>MinDate</li>
            <li>MaxDate</li>
          </ul>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DisplaySettings"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.FirstDayOfWeek"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.MinDate"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.MaxDate"/>
          <link id="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.Loaded">TWinControl.Loaded</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.InitializeWnd" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.InitializeWnd"/>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.DestroyWnd" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.DestroyWnd"/>

      <!-- public -->
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.Create">
        <short>
          Constructor for the class instance.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Create</var> is the constructor for <var>TCustomCalendar</var>. Create calls the inherited <var>Create</var> method, and sets the style, initial bounds, and display settings for the calendar. Create sets the default date / time value to Now, and initializes MinDate and MaxDate to the empty date/time value (0.0).
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.Create">TWinControl.Create</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.Create.TheOwner">
        <short>Owner of the class instance.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.HitTest">
        <short>
          Indicates where a mouse click occurred in the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            HitTest is a TCalendarPart function that indicates where a mouse click occurred in the calendar control. The return value indicates the part of the control clicked, or cpNoWhere when the handle has not been allocated for the control. HitTest ensures that the widget-set specific HitTest method is called.
          </p>
        </descr>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.HitTest.APoint">
        <short>Coordinates where the mouse click occurred.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetCalendarView">
        <short>Gets the current view for the Calendar.</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>GetCalendarView</var> is a <var>TCalendarView</var> function used to get the current view for the calendar control. It calls the GetCurrentView class function in the widgetset class instance when its handle has been allocated. It is used in components like TCalendarDialog and TCalendarPopupForm to determine the active view when a Return or Space key is handled.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCalendarView"/>
          <link id="#lcl.extdlgs.TCalendarDialog">TCalendarDialog</link>
          <link id="#lcl.calendarpopup.TCalendarPopupForm">TCalendarPopupForm</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TCustomCalendar.GetCalendarView.Result">
        <short>Current view for the Calendar.</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.Date">
        <short>
          String representation for the date value on the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Date</var> is a String property that represents the value in DateTime as a String data type.
          </p>
          <p>
            Reading the value for the property causes both Date and DateTime to be read from the widgetset class when its handle has been assigned. FormatDateTime is used to convert the date value to a string type using the ShortDateFormat in the DefaultFormatSettings variable. If the widget handle is not available, the member value is used.
          </p>
          <p>
            Setting a new value in Date causes the value in DateTime to be updated, and the new values are applied to the widgetset class when its handle has been allocated. An EConvertError exception is raised if the new property value is not a valid date using the default format settings.
          </p>
          <p>
            Use DateTime to read or write the date value using a TDateTime data type.
          </p>
          <p>
            Use MinDate and MaxDate to set the lower and upper limits for the dates displayed on the calendar control.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <errors>
          <p>
            Raises an EConvertError exception when Date contains an invalid date value.
          </p>
        </errors>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.MinDate"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.MaxDate"/>
          <link id="#rtl.sysutils.StrToDate">StrToDate</link>
          <link id="#rtl.sysutils.DefaultFormatSettings">DefaultFormatSettings</link>
          <link id="#rtl.sysutils.TFormatSettings">TFormatSettings</link>
          <link id="#rtl.sysutils.EConvertError">EConvertError</link>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.DateTime">
        <short>
          Native data type used for a date value on the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>DateTime</var> is a <var>TDateTime</var> property with the date value for the calendar control. It determines the initial month and year displayed on the control, and the day of the month highlighted at run-time. It is updated (along with Date) when a new date value is selected using the calendar control.
          </p>
          <p>
            Reading the value for the property causes both Date and DateTime members to be retrieved from the widgetset class when its handle has been allocated. If the handle is not available, the member value is used instead.
          </p>
          <p>
            Setting a new value for the property causes the TDateTime value to be validated. When MinDate and MaxDate contain non-zero date/time values that are at least one day apart, the property must in the specified range limits. When MinDate and MaxDate are not assigned, the RTL MinDateTime and MaxDateTime constants are used to limit the range for the date value. An EInvalidDate exception is raised when the date value is not valid for the data type, or not within the required range.
          </p>
          <p>
            FormatDateTime is called to convert the TDateTime value to its string representation in Date. An EConvertError exception is raised if the date is not valid or DefaultFormatSettings contains an invalid ShortDate format.
          </p>
          <p>
            Changes to the property values are sent to the widgetset class instance when its handle has been allocated. This includes values in the Date, DateTime, MinDate, MaxDate, DisplaySettings, and FirstDayOfWeek properties.
          </p>
          <p>
            Use the OnChange, OnDayChanged, OnMonthChanged, or OnYearChanged event handlers to perform actions needed when the date (and its component values) has been modified in the widget for the calendar control.
          </p>
          <remark>
            The control does not use the time portion of the TDateTime data type. The time value is not significant unless the specified time is not valid for the date/time data type.
          </remark>
        </descr>
        <errors>
          <p>
            EConvertError is raised when the value is not a valid for the TDateTime type.
          </p>
          <p>
            EInvalidDate is raised when the date value is not within the range represented by MinDate and MaxDate; raised with the message rsInvalidDateRangeHint.
          </p>
        </errors>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.Date"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.MinDate"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.MaxDate"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnChange"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnYearChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnMonthChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.OnDayChanged"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.DisplaySettings">
        <short>
          <var>DisplaySettings</var> contains options which control the appearance or behavior for the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>DisplaySettings</var> contains options which control the appearance or behavior for the calendar control. DisplaySettings is a set type which contains zero or more TDisplaySetting values, including:
          </p>
          <dl>
            <dt>dsShowHeadings</dt>
            <dd>
              Displays a Month/Year heading. Has no effect on the Windows platform; Month and Year headings are always enabled.
            </dd>
            <dt>dsShowDayNames</dt>
            <dd>
              Displays Day names. Has no effect on the Windows platform; Day names are always enabled.
            </dd>
            <dt>dsNoMonthChange</dt>
            <dd>
              Prevents changing the current month on the calendar. Has no effect on the Windows platform; use MinDate and MaxDate to limit the available calendar dates.
            </dd>
            <dt>dsShowWeekNumbers</dt>
            <dd>Displays week numbers.</dd>
          </dl>
          <remark>
            The value <var>dsStartMonday</var> is no longer available in LCL version 2.2 or higher. It has been replaced by the <var>FirstDayOfWeek</var> property on platforms where the capability is supported (Win32, QT, QT5). This is Delphi compatible, and allows any day of the week to be used as the first day of the week.
          </remark>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.FirstDayOfWeek"/>
          <link id="TDisplaySettings"/>
          <link id="TDisplaySetting"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.FirstDayOfWeek">
        <short>
          Indicates the day of the week displayed as the first column in the calendar grid.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>FirstDayOfWeek</var> is a <var>TCalDayOfWeek</var> property which indicates the day used as the first day of the week. It contains a value from the TCalDayOfWeek enumeration, and determines the order of the cells displayed in the calendar grid. The default value is <var>dowDefault</var>, and indicates the default value provided by the platform or operating system is used.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCalDayOfWeek"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.MaxDate">
        <short>
          Largest date value that can entered or selected using the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>MaxDate</var> is a <var>TDateTime</var> property which contains the largest date value that can be stored or selected using the calendar control.
          </p>
          <p>
            MinDate and MaxDate are used to range check the date value for the control, and to avoid the exception raised when an invalid date is provided. They are also used at run-time to determine the date values that can be displayed and selected using the native calendar control.
          </p>
          <p>
            The default value for MaxDate is an empty TDateTime value (0.0), and indicates that the upper limit has not been assigned. Setting a new value for the property causes the TDateTime value to be validated. The new value in MaxDate must in the range defined by the RTL MinDateTime and MaxDateTime constants.
          </p>
          <p>
            When MinDate and MaxDate contain non-zero date/time values that are at least one day apart, the value in DateTime must in the range represented by the properties. When MinDate and MaxDate are not assigned, the RTL MinDateTime and MaxDateTime constants are used to range limit the value in DateTime. An EInvalidDate exception is raised when the date value is not valid for the data type, or not within the required range.
          </p>
          <remark>
            MinDate and MaxDate are not supported on all platforms. The values may not be available or enforced in some widgetset implementations; GTK2 and GTK3 do not use the values.
          </remark>
        </descr>
        <version>
          Introduced in LCL 2.3, and available in LCL versions 2.4 and higher.
        </version>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.MinDate"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMChanged"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.MinDate">
        <short>
          Smallest date value that can entered or selected using the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>MinDate</var> is a <var>TDateTime</var> property which contains the smallest date value that can be stored or selected using the calendar control.
          </p>
          <p>
            MinDate and MaxDate are used to range check the date value for the control, and to avoid the exception raised when an invalid date is provided. They are also used at run-time to determine the date values that can be displayed and selected using the native calendar control.
          </p>
          <p>
            The default value for MinDate is an empty TDateTime value (0.0), and indicates that the lower limit has not been assigned. Setting a new value for the property causes the TDateTime value to be validated. The new value in MinDate must in the range defined by the RTL MinDateTime and MaxDateTime constants.
          </p>
          <p>
            When MinDate and MaxDate contain non-zero date/time values that are at least one day apart, the value in DateTime must in the range represented by the properties. When MinDate and MaxDate are not assigned, the RTL MinDateTime and MaxDateTime constants are used to range limit the value in DateTime. An EInvalidDate exception is raised when the date value is not valid for the data type, or not within the required range.
          </p>
          <remark>
            MinDate and MaxDate are not supported on all platforms. The values may not be available or enforced in some widgetset implementations; GTK2 and GTK3 do not use the values.
          </remark>
        </descr>
        <version>
          Introduced in LCL 2.3, and available in LCL versions 2.4 and higher.
        </version>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.MaxDate"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMChanged"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.OnChange">
        <short>
          Event handler signalled when the calendar control has been changed.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>OnChange</var> is a <var>TNotifyEvent</var> property with the event handler signalled when the calendar control is changed. It occurs when a day number is clicked on the calendar grid, and when the visible month is changed on the control. OnChange is signalled from the LMChanged, LMDayChanged, LMMonthChanged, and LMYearChanged methods. The event is signalled after the new date value from the widget has been assigned to the members for the DateTime and Date properties.
          </p>
          <p>
            Applications can assign an object procedure to the event handler to respond to the change notification.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.Date"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMYearChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMMonthChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMDayChanged"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.OnDayChanged">
        <short>
          Event handler signalled when the day number in DateTime has been changed using the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>OnDayChanged</var> is a <var>TNotifyEvent</var> property that represents the event handler signalled when the day number in the date/time value for the control has changed. OnDayChanged is signalled from the LMChanged and LMDayChanged methods. It occurs after the new date value from the widget has been assigned to the members for the DateTime and Date properties.
          </p>
          <p>
            Applications can assign an object procedure to the event handler to respond to the change notification.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.Date"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMDayChanged"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.OnMonthChanged">
        <short>
          Event handler signalled when the month number in DateTime has been changed using the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>OnMonthChanged</var> is a <var>TNotifyEvent</var> property that represents the event handler signalled when the month number in the date/time value for the control has changed. OnMonthChanged is signalled from the LMChanged and LMMonthChanged methods. It occurs after the new date value from the widget has been assigned to the members for the DateTime and Date properties.
          </p>
          <p>
            Applications can assign an object procedure to the event handler to respond to the change notification.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.Date"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMMonthChanged"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCustomCalendar.OnYearChanged">
        <short>
          Event handler signalled when the year number in DateTime has been changed using the calendar control.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>OnYearChanged</var> is a <var>TNotifyEvent</var> property that represents the event handler signalled when the year number in the date/time value for the control has changed. OnMonthChanged is signalled from the LMChanged and LMYearChanged methods. It occurs after the new date value from the widget has been assigned to the members for the DateTime and Date properties.
          </p>
          <p>
            Applications can assign an object procedure to the event handler to respond to the change notification.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.Date"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMChanged"/>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar.LMYearChanged"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCalendar">
        <short>
          <var>TCalendar</var> allows selection of a date from a calendar display.
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TCalendar</var> is a <var>TCustomCalendar</var> descendant which implements the graphic control used to select a date value from from the familiar monthly calendar layout. It includes Date and DateTime properties with the selected date as a String or a TDateTime value.
          </p>
          <p>
            TCalendar / TCustomCalendar act as a wrapper for the native calendar control on a given platform. The range of dates allowed in a native calendar control varies by platform. Starting in LCL version 2.4, TCustomCalendar includes MinDate and MaxDate properties which can used to limit the dates displayed on the calendar to a specified minimum and maximum date. Setting Date or DateTime to a value outside the allowed range (when used) causes an EInvalidDate exception to be raised.
          </p>
          <p>
            Please note that MinDate and MaxDate are not supported on all platforms; they are not implemented for GTK2 and GTK3 because the native calendar control does not implement or enforce them.
          </p>
          <p>
            DisplaySettings can be used to control the visual layout and behavior for the calendar. This includes the first day of the week for the calendar layout as well as use of headings, days names, and week numbers.
          </p>
          <p>
            Use the OnChange, OnDayChanged, OnMonthChanged, and OnYearChanged event handlers to perform actions needed when the date or its component values have been modified on the calendar control.
          </p>
          <p>
            Changes made to properties in the control are applied to the widgetset class instance (the native calendar control) when its handle has been allocated.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TCustomCalendar"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- published -->
      <element name="TCalendar.Align" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Align"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.Anchors" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Anchors"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.AutoSize" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.AutoSize"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.BorderSpacing" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.BorderSpacing"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.Constraints" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Constraints"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.DateTime" link="#lcl.calendar.TCustomCalendar.DateTime"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.DisplaySettings" link="#lcl.calendar.TCustomCalendar.DisplaySettings"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.DoubleBuffered" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.DoubleBuffered"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.FirstDayOfWeek" link="#lcl.calendar.TCustomCalendar.FirstDayOfWeek"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.Hint" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Hint"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.MinDate" link="#lcl.calendar.TCustomCalendar.MinDate"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.MaxDate" link="#lcl.calendar.TCustomCalendar.MaxDate"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnChange" link="#lcl.calendar.TCustomCalendar.OnChange"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnChangeBounds" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnChangeBounds"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnClick" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnClick"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnDayChanged" link="#lcl.calendar.TCustomCalendar.OnDayChanged"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnDblClick" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnDblClick"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnEnter" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnEnter"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnExit" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnExit"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnKeyDown" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnKeyDown"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnKeyPress" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnKeyPress"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnKeyUp" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnKeyUp"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMonthChanged" link="#lcl.calendar.TCustomCalendar.OnMonthChanged"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseDown" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseDown"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseEnter" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseEnter"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseLeave" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseLeave"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseMove" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseMove"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseUp" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseUp"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseWheel" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseWheel"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseWheelDown" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseWheelDown"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseWheelUp" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseWheelUp"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseWheelHorz" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseWheelHorz"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseWheelLeft" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseWheelLeft"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnMouseWheelRight" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnMouseWheelRight"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnResize" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.OnResize"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnUTF8KeyPress" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.OnUTF8KeyPress"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.OnYearChanged" link="#lcl.calendar.TCustomCalendar.OnYearChanged"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.ParentDoubleBuffered" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.ParentDoubleBuffered"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.PopupMenu" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.PopupMenu"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.ShowHint" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.ShowHint"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.TabOrder" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.TabOrder"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.Tabstop" link="#lcl.controls.TWinControl.TabStop"/>
      <element name="TCalendar.Visible" link="#lcl.controls.TControl.Visible"/>

      <element name="Register">
        <short>Registers components for use in the Lazarus IDE.</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Register is the procedure used to register components for use in the Lazarus IDE. The following components are added to the Lazarus IDE component palette:
          </p>
          <p>
            <b>Misc</b> Tab
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li>TCalendar</li>
          </ul>
        </descr>
      </element>
    </module>
    <!-- Calendar -->

  </package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
