<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
  <package name="lcl">
    <!--
    ====================================================================
      LazRegions
    ====================================================================
    -->
    <module name="LazRegions">
      <short>Implements non-native regions with support for managing their Z-order</short>
      <descr>
        <p>
          Used to implement clipping regions in <var>TLazCanvas</var>, and regions used in custom-drawn LCL controls.
        </p>
        <p>
          Author: Felipe Monteiro de Carvalho
        </p>
      </descr>

      <!-- unresolved external references -->
      <element name="Classes"/>
      <element name="SysUtils"/>
      <element name="fpcanvas"/>
      <element name="LCLType"/>

      <!-- enumeration type Visibility: default -->
      <element name="TLazRegionFillMode">
        <short>Represents region fill modes used for polygons in Lazarus regions</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Adheres to the nomenclature used in the Windows GDI API.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegionPolygon.FillMode"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddPolygon"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionFillMode.rfmOddEven">
        <short>
        Use the alternate fill mode (fills the area between odd-numbered and even-numbered polygon sides on each scan line)
        </short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionFillMode.rfmWinding">
        <short>
          Use the winding fill mode (fills any region with a non-zero winding value)
        </short>
      </element>

      <!-- array type Visibility: default -->
      <element name="TPointArray">
        <short>Defines an array type used for TPoint values</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TPointArray</var> is an array type used for <var>TPoint</var> instances which define the vertices in a polygon. It is used to implement the <var>Points</var> member in <var>TLazRegionPolygon</var>, and passed as an argument to the <var>AddPolygon</var> method in <var>TLazRegion</var>.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegionPolygon.Points"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddPolygon"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- class Visibility: default -->
      <element name="TLazRegionPart">
        <short>Base class used for rectangular areas in a region</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TLazRegionPart</var> defines the base class used to represent a rectangular area in a region. <var>TLazRegionPart</var> is used as the ancestor for the <var>TLazRegionRect</var> class.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegionRect"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegionPart.GetBoundingRect">
        <short>Gets the rectangle with the Bounds for an area in a region</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>GetBoundingRect</var> is a <var>TRect</var> function used to get the rectangle with the Bounds for a  rectangular area in a region. In TLazRegionPart, the return value contains an empty rectangle (with zero assigned to its Left, Top, Right, Bottom, Width, and Height members).
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- function Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionPart.IsPointInPart">
        <short>
          Indicates if a point with the specified coordinates is within the bounds for the rectangular area
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Always returns <var>False</var> in <var>TLazRegionPart</var>; it uses an empty rectangle as its Bounds (Left, Top, Bottom, and Right set to zero).
          </p>
        </descr>
        <errors></errors>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionPart.IsPointInPart.Result">
        <short>
          True when the coordinates are located in the bounds for the rectangular area
        </short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionPart.IsPointInPart.AX">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionPart.IsPointInPart.AY">
        <short>Vertical coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>

      <!-- class Visibility: default -->
      <element name="TLazRegionRect">
        <short>Implements a region defined by a TRect structure</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TLazRegionRect</var> is a <var>TLazRegionPart</var> descendant which implements a region as a rectangular area. It includes a <var>Rect</var> member used to store the <var>TRect</var> with the bounds for the region. It also provides an overridden <var>IsPointInPart</var> method to examine the Rect member when locating a point in the region. Instances of TLazRegionRect are created when the <var>AddRectangle</var> method in <var>TLazRegion</var> is called.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegionPart"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.Parts"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddRectangle"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- variable Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionRect.Rect">
        <short>Rectangle with the bounds that defines the region</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Rect</var> is a <var>TRect</var> member which contains the rectangular area that is the bounds for the region.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- function Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionRect.IsPointInPart">
        <short>
          Indicates if a point with the specified coordinates is within the rectangle used as the bounds for the region
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Overrides the method in the ancestor class to use the <var>Rect</var> member as the bounds for the region.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionRect.IsPointInPart.Result">
        <short>
          True when the coordinates are located in the bounds rectangle for the region
        </short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionRect.IsPointInPart.AX">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionRect.IsPointInPart.AY">
        <short>Vertical coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>

      <!-- class Visibility: default -->
      <element name="TLazRegionPolygon">
        <short>Represents a region defined as a series of vertices for a polygon</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TLazRegionPolygon</var> is a <var>TLazRegionPart</var> descendant which implements a region as a polygonal area defined by a series of vertices.
          </p>
          <p>
            The <var>Points</var> member contains the <var>TPoint</var> values that define the vertices for the polygon. <var>FillMode</var> defines how the interior of the polygon is fillled, as uses values like those defined for the Windows GDI API. An overridden <var>IsPointInPart</var> is provided to detemine if a point is within the bounds for the polygonal area.
          </p>
          <p>
            Instances of TLazRegionPolygon are created when the <var>AddPolygon</var> method in <var>TLazRegion</var> is called.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddPolygon"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.Parts"/>
          <link id="TLazRegionPart"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- variable Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionPolygon.Points">
        <short>Array of TPoint values that define the vertices for the polygonal region</short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- variable Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionPolygon.FillMode">
        <short>Fill mode used for the polygon</short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- function Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionPolygon.IsPointInPart">
        <short>
          Indicates if a point with the specified coordinates is within the vertices for the polygonal region
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>IsPointInPart</var> is an overridden <var>Boolean</var> function which indicates if a point with the specified coordinates is within the vertices for the polygonal region.
          </p>
          <p>
            <var>IsPointInPart</var> calls the <var>IsPointInPolygon</var> routine to get the return value for the method. The return value is <b>True</b> when the point in <var>AX</var> and <var>AY</var> is located inside the polygon vertices defined in the <var>Points</var> member.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="IsPointInPolygon"/>
          <link id="TLazRegionPolygon.Points"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionPolygon.IsPointInPart.Result">
        <short>True when the point occurs inside the vertices for the polygonal region</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionPolygon.IsPointInPart.AX">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionPolygon.IsPointInPart.AY">
        <short>Vertical coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegionEllipse">
        <short>Implements a region defined as an Ellipse</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TLazRegionEllipse</var> is a <var>TLazRegionPart</var> descendant which implements a region defined as an elliptical area with the specified vertex and co-vertex. The <var>X1</var>, <var>X2</var>, <var>Y1</var>, and <var>Y2</var> members are provided to represent the horizontal and vertical coordinates for the vertex and co-vertex points.
          </p>
          <p>
            Instances of <var>TLazRegionEllipse</var> are created when the <var>AddEllipse</var> method in <var>TLazRegion</var> is called.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddEllipse"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.Parts"/>
          <link id="TLazRegionPart"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegionEllipse.X1">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the vertex</short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegionEllipse.Y1">
        <short>Vertical coordinate for the vertex</short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegionEllipse.X2">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the co-vertex</short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegionEllipse.Y2">
        <short>Vertical coordinate for the co-vertex</short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegionEllipse.IsPointInPart">
        <short>
          Indicates if the specified point is located inside the elliptical area for the region
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            The equation for the inner area of an axis aligned ellipse is:
          </p>
          <code>(X/a)^2 + (Y/b)^2 &lt;= 1</code>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionEllipse.IsPointInPart.Result">
        <short>True when the specified point is located inside the area for the ellipse</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionEllipse.IsPointInPart.AX">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionEllipse.IsPointInPart.AY">
        <short>Vertical coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TFPCustomRegion">
        <short></short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
        <version>
          Defined for FPC version 2.6. Defined in <file>fpcanvas.pp</file> for later FPC  versions.
        </version>
      </element>

      <element name="TFPCustomRegion.GetBoundingRect">
        <short></short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
        <version>
          Defined for FPC version 2.6. Defined in <file>fpcanvas.pp</file> for later FPC  versions.
        </version>
      </element>
      <element name="TFPCustomRegion.GetBoundingRect.Result">
        <short></short>
        <version>
          Defined for FPC version 2.6. Defined in <file>fpcanvas.pp</file> for later FPC  versions.
        </version>
      </element>

      <element name="TFPCustomRegion.IsPointInRegion">
        <short></short>
        <version>
          Defined for FPC version 2.6. Defined in <file>fpcanvas.pp</file> for later FPC  versions.
        </version>
      </element>
      <element name="TFPCustomRegion.IsPointInRegion.Result">
        <short></short>
        <version>
          Defined for FPC version 2.6. Defined in <file>fpcanvas.pp</file> for later FPC  versions.
        </version>
      </element>
      <element name="TFPCustomRegion.IsPointInRegion.AX">
        <short></short>
        <version>
          Defined for FPC version 2.6. Defined in <file>fpcanvas.pp</file> for later FPC  versions.
        </version>
      </element>
      <element name="TFPCustomRegion.IsPointInRegion.AY">
        <short></short>
        <version>
          Defined for FPC version 2.6. Defined in <file>fpcanvas.pp</file> for later FPC  versions.
        </version>
      </element>

      <!-- class Visibility: default -->
      <element name="TLazRegion">
        <short>Represents a custom region in the Lazarus LCL</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TLazRegion</var> is a <var>TFPCustomRegion</var> descendant which represents a region as used in the Lazarus LCL. It is used to implement the clipping region in <var>TLazCanvas</var>, and in custom-drawn windowed LCL controls. The region is composed of <var>TLazRegionPart</var> descendants representing the rectangles, polygons, and ellipses that define the display area on a device. TLazRegion provides overridden methods to query information for the composite display area.
          </p>
          <p>
            The parts of a region should all be inside valid areas for the region. If a combine operation removes an area in the region, then the area should be removed from all parts for the region. There is no z-order for the <var>Parts</var>, they are all validly inside the region area.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegionWithChilds"/>
          <link id="#LCL.LazCanvas.TLazCanvas"/>
          <link id="#LCL.LazCanvas.TLazCanvasState.ClipRegion"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- variable Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegion.Parts">
        <short>
          List with the Rectangles, Polygons, and Ellipses that define the display area for the region
        </short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- variable Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegion.IsSimpleRectRegion">
        <short>Indicates whether this region is composed of a single rectangular part</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Use <var>Rect</var> to access the <var>TRect</var> structure with the bounds for the rectangular region.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- variable Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegion.Rect">
        <short>TRect instance with the bounds for the region</short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- constructor Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegion.Create">
        <short>Constructor for the class instance</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Create</var> is the constructor for the class instance. Create calls the inherited constructor to initialize the class instance. Create allocates resources needed for the <var>Parts</var> member, and sets the default value for <var>IsSimpleRectRegion</var> to <b>True</b>.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- destructor Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegion.Destroy">
        <short>Destructor for the class instance</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Destroy</var> is the overridden destructor for the class instance. Destroy ensures that resource allocated for the <var>Parts</var> member are freed. Destroy calls the inherited destructor prior to exiting from the method.
          </p>
          <remark>
            Destroy does not call <var>Parts.Clear</var> prior to freeing the <var>Parts</var> member; that action is performed in the destructor for the <var>TFPList</var> class instance.
          </remark>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegion.Assign">
        <short>Stores values from ASrcRegion in the current class instance</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Calls <var>Clear</var> to remove any items stored in <var>Parts</var>.
            Calls <var>AddPartsFromRegion</var> to capture the values from the source region.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.Assign.ASrcRegion">
        <short>Region with the values stored in the method</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegion.Clear">
        <short>Frees all of the TLazRegionPart instances in Parts, and clears the list</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Frees all of the <var>TLazRegionPart</var> instances in the <var>Parts</var> member, and clears the list.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegion.CombineWith">
        <short>Combines the specified source region using the given region operation</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>ASrcRegion</var> is the source region with the Parts applied in the method.
          </p>
          <p>
            <var>AOperation</var> can contain a Combine Region flag that includes:
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li>RGN_AND (1)</li>
            <li>RGN_OR (2)</li>
            <li>RGN_XOR (3)</li>
            <li>RGN_DIFF (4)</li>
            <li>RGN_COPY(5)</li>
          </ul>
          <remark>
            In the current LCL version, only <var>RGN_COPY</var> and <var>RGN_OR</var> are implemented; all other values are ignored and no actions are performed in the method. RGN_COPY causes the Parts in ASrcRegion to be assigned to the Parts in the current class instance. RGN_OR cause the Parts in ASrcRegion to the be added to the Parts in the current class instance.
          </remark>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.CombineWith.ASrcRegion">
        <short>Source region with values applied in the method</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.CombineWith.AOperation">
        <short>Combine region flag with the operation to perform for the subregions</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegion.GetRegionKind">
        <short>Gets the type of region represented in the class instance</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>GetRegionKind</var> is a <var>Longint</var> function used to get the type of region represented in the class instance. The return value adheres to the region flag values used in the Windows GDI API, and can include one of the following:
          </p>
          <dl>
            <dt>COMPLEXREGION (3)</dt>
            <dd>
              The region has more than one rectangle, polygon, or ellipse. Used when IsSimpleRectRegion is False.
            </dd>
            <dt>SIMPLEREGION (2)</dt>
            <dd>
              The region is a simple rectangle defined using the Rect member. Used when IsSimpleRectRegion is True, and Rect is not an empty rectangle (Left, Top, Bottom, and Right all contain zero).
            </dd>
            <dt>NULLREGION (1)</dt>
            <dd>
              The region has an empty value in its Rect member (Left, Top, Width, and Height all contain zero).
            </dd>
            <dt>REGION_ERROR (0)</dt>
            <dd>An error occurred. Not used in GetRegionKind.</dd>
          </dl>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.GetRegionKind.Result">
        <short>Region flag value for the class instance</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegion.IsSimpleRectEmpty">
        <short>
          Indicates whether the Rect member contains empty or invalid rectangle coordinates
        </short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.IsSimpleRectEmpty.Result">
        <short>
          True when the dimensions for the rectangle are invalid
        </short>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegion.AddPart">
        <short>Adds the specified part as a subregion in the Parts member</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>AddPart</var> is a procedure used to add the specified <var>TLazRegionPart</var> in <var>APart</var> to the <var>Parts</var> member in the class instance. AddPart calls the <var>TFPList.Add</var> method to store the value in APart in the list. AddPart calls <var>DoChangeToComplexRegion</var> to update  <var>IsSimpleRectRegion</var> to reflect the current composition for the region.
          </p>
          <p>
            AddPart is used in the implementation of the <var>AddRectangle</var>, <var>AddPolygon</var>, and <var>AddEllipse</var> methods.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegion.DoChangeToComplexRegion"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.IsSimpleRectRegion"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddRectangle"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddPolygon"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddEllipse"/>
          <link id="TLazRegionPart"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddPart.APart">
        <short>TLazRegionPart (or descendant) added in the method</short>
      </element>

      <!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddRectangle">
        <short>Adds the specified TRect instance to the Parts member</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>AddRectangle</var> is a procedure used to add a rectangular region defined by the <var>TRect</var> instance in <var>ARect</var> to the <var>Parts</var> member. AddRectangle creates a <var>TLazRegionRect</var> instance and assigns ARect to its <var>Rect</var> member. AddRectangle calls <var>AddPart</var> to store the TLazRegionRect instance in Parts.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegionRect"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddPart"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.Parts"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddRectangle.ARect">
        <short>TRect instance with the rectangular region added in the method</short>
      </element>

      <!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddPolygon">
        <short>Adds a polygonal area with the specified vertices to the region</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>AddPolygon</var> is a procedure used to add a polygonal area with the specified vertices to the region. <var>APoints</var> is an array with <var>TPoint</var> instances that define each of the vertices for the polygon. <var>AFillMode</var> is a <var>TLazRegionFillMode</var> value that defines the fill mode for the polygonal area.
          </p>
          <p>
            AddPolygon creates a <var>TLazRegionPolygon</var> instance that is used to store the area definition in the <var>Parts</var> member. The arguments to the method are assigned to the <var>Points</var> and <var>FillMode</var> members in the new class instance. AddPolygon calls <var>AddPart</var> to store the new TLazRegionPolygon instance in Parts.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddPart"/>
          <link id="TLazRegionPolygon"/>
          <link id="TLazRegionPolygon.Points"/>
          <link id="TLazRegionPolygon.FillMode"/>
          <link id="TPointArray"/>
          <link id="TLazRegionFillMode"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddPolygon.APoints">
        <short>Array of TPoint instances representing the vertices for the polygon</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddPolygon.AFillMode">
        <short>TLazRegionFillMode value used for the polygon</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegion.AddEllipse">
        <short>Adds an elliptical area with the specified co-vertices to the region</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>AddEllipse</var> is a procedure used to add an elliptical area with the specified co-vertices to the region. <var>AX1</var> and <var>AY1</var> is the point where the endpoint for the long axis is located. <var>AX2</var> and <var>AY2</var> is the point where the endpoint for the short axis is located. Each point is located perpendicular to the opposing axis, and its diameter bisects the opposing axis.
          </p>
          <p>
            AddEllipse creates an instance of <var>TLazRegionEllipse</var> and assigns the arguments to the corresponding members in the new class instance. AddEllipse calls the <var>AddPart</var> method to store the new TLazRegionEllipse instance in the <var>Parts</var> member.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegion.Parts"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddPart"/>
          <link id="TLazRegionEllipse"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddEllipse.AX1">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the endpoint of the major axis</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddEllipse.AY1">
        <short>Vertical  coordinate for the endpoint of the major axis</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddEllipse.AX2">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the endpoint of the minor axis</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddEllipse.AY2">
        <short>Vertical coordinate for the endpoint of the minor axis</short>
      </element>

      <!-- procedure Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegion.SetAsSimpleRectRegion">
        <short>Sets the area for the region to the specified rectangle</short>
        <descr></descr>
        <errors></errors>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.SetAsSimpleRectRegion.ARect">
        <short>TRect with the bounds for the region</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegion.AddPartsFromRegion">
        <short>
          Adds the region (and any subregions) from ASrcRegion to the current class instance
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>AddPartsFromRegion</var> is a procedure used to add the region in <var>ASrcRegion</var> to the current class instance. ASrcRegion can be represented as a simple rectangular region, or a complex region using rectangles, polygons, and/or ellipses.
          </p>
          <p>
            AddPartsFromRegion ensures that the <var>Rect</var> or <var>Parts</var> members from ASrcRegion are combined in the correct manner with the values in Rect or Parts for the current class instance. The value in <var>IsSimpleRectRegion</var> is set to <b>False</b> if it was necessary to add entries to the <var>Parts</var> member in the method.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegion.Rect"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.IsSimpleRectRegion"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.Parts"/>
          <link id="TLazRegion.AddPart"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.AddPartsFromRegion.ASrcRegion">
        <short>Region with the values added in the method</short>
      </element>

      <element name="TLazRegion.DoChangeToComplexRegion">
        <short>
          Adds the value in Rect to the Parts member, and resets the value in  IsSimpleRectRegion
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>DoChangeToComplexRegion</var> is a procedure used to change the region from a simple rectangle to a complex region as defined in the <var>Parts</var> member. DoChangeToComplexRegion uses the values from <var>IsSimpleRectRegion</var> and <var>IsSimpleRectEmpty</var> to determine if any actions are required in the method.  No actions are performed when IsSimpleRectRegion is <b>False</b>, or when IsSimpleRectEmpty returns <b>True</b>.
          </p>
          <p>
            DoChangeToComplexRegion changes the value in IsSimpleRectRegion to <b>False</b>, and calls <var>AddRectangle</var> to store the value in <var>Rect</var> in the <var>Parts</var> member.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- function Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegion.GetBoundingRect">
        <short>Gets the bounds for the region as a rectangle</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>GetBoundingRect</var> is a <var>TRect</var> function used to get the rectangle structure with the bounds for the region. GetBoundingRect uses the value in the <var>Rect</var> member as the return value for the method.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.GetBoundingRect.Result">
        <short>TRect with the bounds for the region</short>
      </element>

      <!-- function Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegion.IsPointInRegion">
        <short>Checks whether the specified point is inside the region</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Checks if the specified point is inside the display area for the region. Uses the value in <var>IsSimpleRectRegion</var> to determine whether <var>Rect</var> contains the bounds for the region. When it contains <b>False</b>, the values in the <var>Parts</var> member are used to determine the return value.
          </p>
          <p>
            Returns <b>True</b> when the specified point is located inside the rectangle or one of the subregions.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.IsPointInRegion.Result">
        <short>
          True when the point is located inside the rectangle or one of the subregions that define the bounds for the region
        </short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.IsPointInRegion.AX">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegion.IsPointInRegion.AY">
        <short>Vertical coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>

      <!-- class Visibility: default -->
      <element name="TLazRegionWithChilds">
        <short>Implement a region which can have other regions as children</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TLazRegionWithChilds</var> is a <var>TLazRegion</var> descendant which implements a region which can hold a list of other region holders. Use <var>Parent</var> to access the complex region which owns the current class instance. Use <var>Childs</var> to access the list of subregions for the class instance.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- variable Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionWithChilds.Parent">
        <short>Complex region which hosts the subregions in the current class instance</short>
        <descr>
          <remark>
            <var>Parent</var> is not maintain in methods for the class instance; it is available for use in widget set classes which utilize the region.
          </remark>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- variable Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionWithChilds.Childs">
        <short>List of subregions for the current class instance</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            The order in this list is also the Z-Order of the sub regions inside it. The element with index zero is the bottom-most one.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- variable Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionWithChilds.UserData">
        <short>Contains an available link to another object</short>
        <descr>
          Contains an available link to another object.
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- constructor Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionWithChilds.Create">
        <short>Constructor for the class instance</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Create</var> is the overridden constructor for the class instance. Create calls the inherited constructor to initialize the class instance, and allocates resources needed for the <var>Childs</var> member.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- destructor Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionWithChilds.Destroy">
        <short>Destructor for the class instance</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>Destroy</var> is the overridden destructor for the class instance. Destroy ensures that resources allocated to the <var>Childs</var> member are freed. Destroy calls the inherited destructor prior to exiting from the method.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- function Visibility: public -->
      <element name="TLazRegionWithChilds.IsPointInRegion">
        <short>Indicates if the specified point is within the bounds for the region</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Returns itself or a child, depending on where the point was found, or nil if the point is neither in the region nor in any children.
          </p>
          <p>
            Part of the behavior is implemented in TLazRegionWithChilds.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionWithChilds.IsPointInRegion.Result">
        <short>
          True when the point is within the bounds for one of the child areas in the region
        </short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionWithChilds.IsPointInRegion.AX">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLazRegionWithChilds.IsPointInRegion.AY">
        <short>Vertical coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>

      <!-- function Visibility: default -->
      <element name="IsPointInPolygon">
        <short>
          Determines if the specified point is inside the vertices for the specified polygon
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            The function will return True if the point at AX, AY is inside the specified  polygon. Returns False if it is not.
          </p>
          <p>
            Original C code:
            <url href="http://www.visibone.com/inpoly/inpoly.c.txt">
              http://www.visibone.com/inpoly/inpoly.c.txt
            </url>.
          </p>
          <p>
            Translated from C to Pascal by: Felipe Monteiro de Carvalho.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TLazRegionPolygon.IsPointInPart"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="IsPointInPolygon.Result">
        <short>
          True when the specified point is located within the polygon using the specified vertices
        </short>
      </element>
      <element name="IsPointInPolygon.AX">
        <short>Horizontal coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>
      <element name="IsPointInPolygon.AY">
        <short>Vertical coordinate for the point</short>
      </element>
      <element name="IsPointInPolygon.APolygon">
        <short>Array with the TPoint values that define the vertices for the polygon</short>
      </element>

    </module>
    <!-- LazRegions -->
  </package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
