<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
  <package name="lazutils">
    <!--
      ====================================================================
        FPCAdds
      ====================================================================
    -->
    <module name="FPCAdds">
      <short>
        Contains additional types and routines not currently available in FPC
      </short>
      <descr>
        <file>fpcadds.pas</file> contains code in its initialization section to set the code page for conversions and the <var>RTL</var> file system to <var>CP_UTF8</var>. The initialization code is included only for platforms or OS-es where the <var>RTL</var> (<b>Run-Time Library</b>) is UTF-8-enabled.
      </descr>

      <!-- unresolved type references Visibility: default -->
      <element name="Classes"/>
      <element name="SysUtils"/>

      <element name="TStreamSeekType">
        <short>Alias to the Int64 type used as the origin for TStream seek operations</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Used in the implementation of classes including:
          </p>
          <ul>
            <li>TBitmap</li>
            <li>TIcon</li>
            <li>TSharedCursorImage</li>
            <li>TImageList</li>
            <li>TClipboard</li>
          </ul>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TMemStreamSeekType">
        <short>Alias to the PtrInt type used as the origin for TMemoryStream seek operations</short>
        <descr>
          Used in the implementation of <var>TSynCustomExporter</var>.
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TCompareMemSize">
        <short>Alias to the PtrUInt type used when comparing memory blocks</short>
        <descr>
          Used in the implementation of <var>TSynCustomExporter</var> and <var>TGraphic</var>.
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="PHandle">
        <short>Type used for a pointer to a THandle type</short>
        <descr>
          Also defined in <file>lcltype.pp</file>.
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="StrToWord">
        <short>Converts the value in a String to a Word data type</short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="StrToWord.Result">
        <short>Word value calculated for the specified String</short>
      </element>
      <element name="StrToWord.s">
        <short>String value examined in the method</short>
      </element>

      <element name="AlignToPtr">
        <short>
          Aligns the specified pointer to the boundaries required for the FPC compiler
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>AlignToPtr</var> is a <var>Pointer</var> function used to adjust the pointer specified in <var>p</var> to the boundaries required for the FPC compiler. AlignToPtr is influenced by the <b>FPC_REQUIRES_PROPER_ALIGNMENT</b> compiler define; when it is defined, the Align routine is called to adjust the pointer to the size required for Pointer data types. When it is not defined, the pointer in <var>p</var> does not require alignment, and is used as the return value.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="AlignToInt"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="AlignToPtr.p">
        <short>Pointer affected in the routine</short>
      </element>

      <element name="AlignToInt">
        <short>
          Aligns the specified pointer to the size of an Integer data type
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>AlignToInt</var> is a <var>Pointer</var> function used to adjust the pointer in <var>p</var> to the size needed for an <var>Integer</var> data type. <var>AlignToInt</var> is influenced by the <b>FPC_REQUIRES_PROPER_ALIGNMENT</b> compiler define; when it is defined, the <var>Align</var> routine is called to adjust the pointer size to the boundaries required for an <var>Integer</var> data type. When it is not defined, the pointer in <var>p</var> is used as the return value.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <notes>
          <note>Not currently used in any other units.</note>
        </notes>
        <seealso>
          <link id="AlignToPtr"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="AlignToInt.p">
        <short></short>
      </element>

    </module>
    <!-- FPCAdds -->
  </package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
