<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
  <package name="lazutils">
    <!--
    ====================================================================
      laz2_XMLWrite
    ====================================================================
    -->
    <module name="laz2_XMLWrite">
      <short>
        Provides routines used to write XML content to a file, text file, or stream
      </short>
      <descr>
        <p>
          <var>laz2_xmlwrite.pas</var> provides procedures and types used to write XML content to a file, text file, or stream. laz2_xmlwrite.pas has classes in its implementation section that are used to perform serialization of XML content to the storage destination.
        </p>
        <p>
          Copyright (c) 1999-2000 by Sebastian Guenther, sg@freepascal.org <br/>
          Modified in 2006 by Sergei Gorelkin, sergei_gorelkin@mail.ru <br/>
          Converted to use UTF-8 instead of widestrings by Mattias Gaertner.
        </p>
      </descr>

      <!-- unresolved externals -->
      <element name="Classes"/>
      <element name="SysUtils"/>
      <element name="LazUTF8"/>
      <element name="lazUTF8Classes"/>
      <element name="laz2_DOM"/>
      <element name="laz2_XMLUtils"/>

      <!-- enumeration type Visibility: default -->
      <element name="TXMLWriterFlag">
        <short>
          Represent options enabled when writing XML content
        </short>
        <descr>
          <var>TXMLWriterFlag</var> is an enumerated type with values that represent options enabled when writing XML content. Values in TXMLWriterFlag are stored in the <var>TXMLWriterFlags</var> set type, and passed as an argument to the WriteXMLFile and WriteXML routines.
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TXMLWriterFlags"/>
          <ink id="WriteXMLFile"/>
          <ink id="WriteXML"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <!-- enumeration value Visibility: default -->
      <element name="TXMLWriterFlag.xwfSpecialCharsInAttributeValue">
        <short>
          Enables writing Carriage Return (Decimal 13) characters in attribute values instead of the numeric character entity &amp;xD;
        </short>
      </element>
      <element name="TXMLWriterFlag.xwfPreserveWhiteSpace">
        <short>Preserves whitespace in DOM Text nodes</short>
      </element>

      <!-- set type Visibility: default -->
      <element name="TXMLWriterFlags">
        <short>Set type used to store TXMLWriterFlag values</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TXMLWriterFlags</var> is a set type used to store 0 or more values from the <var>TXMLWriterFlag</var> enumeration. TXMLWriterFlags indicates the options enabled when writing XML content. TXMLWriterFlags is the type passed as an argument to the <var>WriteXMLFile</var> procedure.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="TXMLWriterFlag"/>
          <link id="WriteXMLFile"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- procedure Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXMLFile">
        <short>
          Writes an XML document to a file, text file, or stream
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>WriteXMLFile</var> is an overloaded procedure used to write an XML document to a file, text file, or stream. Overloaded variants provide the implementation details for each of the destinations, and create either TTextXMLWriter or TStreamXMLWriter class instances to store the XML document.
          </p>
          <p>
            AFileName indicates the file name on the local file system where the XML content is stored. AFileName can contain UTF-8 encoded values, and must represent a valid file name. If the file in AFileName already exists, an exception will be raised.
          </p>
          <p>
            Flags contains values from the TXMLWriterFlag enumeration. Use Flags to enable XML writing options in the routine. The default value for the argument is an empty set (<b>[]</b>), and indicates that no options are enabled in the routine.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="WriteXML"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXMLFile.doc">
        <short>XML document written in the routine</short>
      </element>

      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXMLFile.AFileName">
        <short>File name where the XML content is stored</short>
      </element>

      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXMLFile.AFile">
        <short>Text file type where the content is written</short>
      </element>

      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXMLFile.AStream">
        <short>Stream where the XML document is stored</short>
      </element>

      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXMLFile.Flags">
        <short>Options enabled when writing the XML content</short>
      </element>

      <!-- procedure Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXML">
        <short>
          Writes a DOM Node to a file, text file, or stream
        </short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>WriteXML</var> is an overloaded procedure used to write a DOM Node to a file, text file, or stream. WriteXML calls one of the overloaded WriteXMLFile routines for a specific destination.
          </p>
          <p>
            Element is a TDOMNode parameter that represents the DOM Document Node with the XML content written in the method. WriteXML ensures that Element is cast to a TXMLDocument type when calling the WriteXMLFile routine.
          </p>
          <p>
            AFileName indicates the file name on the local file system where the XML content is stored. AFileName can contain UTF-8 encoded values, and must represent a valid file name. If the file in AFileName already exists, an exception will be raised.
          </p>
          <p>
            Flags contains values from the TXMLWriterFlag enumeration. Use Flags to enable XML writing options in the routine. The default value for the argument is an empty set (<b>[]</b>), and indicates that no options are enabled in the routine.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="WriteXMLFile"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXML.Element">
        <short>DOM Node with the XML content written in the method</short>
      </element>

      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXML.AFileName">
        <short>File name where the XML content is stored</short>
      </element>

      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXML.AFile">
        <short>Text file type where the content is written</short>
      </element>

      <!-- argument Visibility: default -->
      <element name="WriteXML.AStream">
        <short>Stream where the XML document is stored</short>
      </element>

      <element name="WriteXML.Flags">
        <short>Options enabled when writing the XML content</short>
      </element>

    </module>
    <!-- laz2_XMLWrite -->

  </package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
