<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<fpdoc-descriptions>
  <package name="lazutils">
    <!--
    ============================================================================
      LazTracer
    ============================================================================
    -->
    <module name="LazTracer">

      <!-- unresolved external references -->
      <element name="Classes"/>
      <element name="SysUtils"/>
      <element name="Laz_AVL_Tree"/>
      <element name="LazLoggerBase"/>
      <element name="LazUtilities"/>
      <element name="LazUtilsStrConsts"/>

      <element name="TStackTracePointers">
        <short>Array type used for Pointers to code addresses</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>TStackTracePointers</var> is an <var>Array</var> type which contains Pointers to code addresses. TStackTracePointers is the type passed as an argument to the <var>GetStackTracePointers</var> and <var>StackTraceAsString</var> routines. It is also the type used to implement the <var>CreationStack</var> and <var>DestructionStack</var> members in <var>TDebugLCLItemInfo</var>.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="GetStackTracePointers"/>
          <link id="StackTraceAsString"/>
          <link id="#LCL.LCLProc.TDebugLCLItemInfo"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="TLineInfoCacheItem">
        <short>
          Record type used to store a pointer to a code address and its additional information
        </short>
        <descr></descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="PLineInfoCacheItem"/>
          <link id="GetLineInfo"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="TLineInfoCacheItem.Addr">
        <short>Pointer to the address for a source code symbol</short>
      </element>
      <element name="TLineInfoCacheItem.Info">
        <short>Contains additional information about the code address and its origin</short>
      </element>

      <element name="PLineInfoCacheItem">
        <short>Pointer to a TLineInfoCacheItem type</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            Used in the implementation of the <var>GetLineInfo</var> routine.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="GetLineInfo"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="RaiseGDBException">
        <short>Raises an exception in the GDB debugger</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>RaiseGDBException</var> is a procedure used to raise an exception in the GDB debugger. Normally, GDB does not catch FPC <var>Exception</var> objects. This procedure raises a standard <b>"Division By Zero"</b> exception, which <b>IS</b> caught by GDB. This allows a program to be stopped in the debugger without extra GDB  configuration.
          </p>
          <remark>
            Please note: For the Amiga platform, Division by Zero errors are not catchable. The program will simply crash.
          </remark>
          <p>
            <var>Msg</var> contains the value used as the message in the exception.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="RaiseGDBException.Msg">
        <short>Value for the message in the exception</short>
      </element>

      <element name="RaiseAndCatchException">
        <short>Raises an exception that is caught and handled in an application</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>RaiseAndCatchException</var> is a procedure used to generate an <var>Exception</var> that is caught and handled by an application.
          </p>
          <remark>
            Please note: For the Amiga platform, Division by Zero errors are not catchable. The program will simply crash.
          </remark>
        </descr>
        <seealso></seealso>
      </element>

      <element name="GetStackTrace">
        <short>Retrieves backtrace information for code addresses</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>GetStackTrace</var> is a <var>String</var> function used to retrieve backtrace information for code addresses in a string format.
          </p>
          <p>
            Calls <var>GetLineInfo</var> to get information for the code addresses, using the value in <var>UseCache</var> as an argument. UseCache indicates if cached line information from an internal AVL tree can be used in the routine. When UseCache contains <b>False</b>, the <var>BackTraceStrFunc</var> in <file>lclproc.pas</file> initialization section is called to get the line information for each of the backtrace addresses.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="GetLineInfo"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="GetStackTrace.Result">
        <short>String with information about backtrace addresses</short>
      </element>
      <element name="GetStackTrace.UseCache">
        <short>Indicates if cached line information can be used in the routine</short>
      </element>

      <element name="GetStackTracePointers">
        <short>Retrieve the addresses and information for a code address and its callers</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>GetStackTracePointers</var> is a procedure used to retrieve the addresses and information for a code address and its callers.
          </p>
          <p>
            <var>AStack</var> is the array where pointers to code addresses for calling routines are stored.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="StackTraceAsString"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="GetStackTracePointers.AStack">
        <short>Array where pointers to code addresses are stored</short>
      </element>

      <element name="StackTraceAsString">
        <short>Gets a string with backtrace information for the specified call stack</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>StackTraceAsString</var> is a <var>String</var> function used to get backtrace information for the  code addresses specified in <var>AStack</var>. The return value contains lines with the values from <var>GetLineInfo</var> for each of the code addresses.
          </p>
          <p>
            <var>UseCache</var> indicates if cached line information from an internal AVL tree can be used in the routine. It is passed as an argument in calls to the <var>GetLineInfo</var> routine.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso>
          <link id="GetLineInfo"/>
          <link id="TStackTracePointers"/>
        </seealso>
      </element>
      <element name="StackTraceAsString.Result">
        <short>String with backtrace information for the call stack</short>
      </element>
      <element name="StackTraceAsString.AStack">
        <short>Array of pointers to code addresses examined in the routine</short>
      </element>
      <element name="StackTraceAsString.UseCache">
        <short>Indicates if cached line information can be used in the routine</short>
      </element>

      <element name="GetLineInfo">
        <short>Gets information about the specified code address</short>
        <descr>
          <p>
            <var>GetLineInfo</var> is a <var>String</var> function used to get information about the code address specified in <var>Addr</var>.
          </p>
          <p>
            <var>UseCache</var> indicates if cached line information from an internal AVL tree can be used in the routine. When UseCache contains <b>False</b>, the <var>BackTraceStrFunc</var> in the <file>lclproc.pas</file> initialization section is called to get the line information for each of the backtrace addresses.
          </p>
        </descr>
        <seealso/>
      </element>
      <element name="GetLineInfo.Result">
        <short>String with information about the code address</short>
      </element>
      <element name="GetLineInfo.Addr">
        <short>The code address examined in the routine</short>
      </element>
      <element name="GetLineInfo.UseCache">
        <short>Indicates if locally cached line information can be used in the routine</short>
      </element>

    </module>
    <!-- LazTracer -->
  </package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
