<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--

Documentation for LCL (Lazarus Component Library) and LazUtils (Lazarus 
Utilities) are published under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 
International public license.

https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode.txt
https://gitlab.com/freepascal.org/lazarus/lazarus/-/blob/main/docs/cc-by-sa-4-0.txt

Copyright (c) 1997-2024, by the Lazarus Development Team.

-->
<fpdoc-descriptions>
<package name="lazutils">
<!--
====================================================================
lazutf16
====================================================================
-->
<module name="lazutf16">
<short>
Contains routines used for UTF-16 character and string operations.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<file>lazutf16.pas</file> includes string routines which are based on UTF-16
implementations, although it might also include routines for other encodings.
</p>
<p>
A UTF-16 based implementation for LowerCase, for example, is faster in
WideString and UnicodeString then the default UTF-8 implementation.
</p>
<p>
Currently this unit includes only UTF8LowerCaseViaTables which is based on
a UTF-16 table, but it might be extended to include various UTF-16 routines.
</p>
<p>
<file>lazutf16.pas</file> is part of the <file>LazUtils</file> package.
</p>
</descr>

<element name="UTF16CharacterLength">
<short>
Gets the length of the UTF-16 character in the specified PWideChar value as a 
number Word values.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Uses the endian-ness for the platform. UTF16CharacterLength checks the first 
Word value in <var>p</var> to determine the return value for the routine, and 
can contain:
</p>
<dl>
<dt>0</dt>
<dd>
Returned when the value in the <var>p</var> argument is <b>Nil</b>.
</dd>
<dt>1</dt>
<dd>
Returned when the first Word value in <var>p</var> argument is outside the 
range $D800..$DFFF.
</dd>
<dt>2</dt>
<dd>
Returned when the first Word value in <var>p</var> argument is included in the 
range $D800..$DFFF.  
</dd>
</dl>
</descr>
</element>
<element name="UTF16CharacterLength.Result">
<short>
Length of the UTF-16 character in the specified value, or 0 when <b>Nil</b>.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16CharacterLength.p">
<short>
PWideChar value examined in the routine.
</short>
</element>

<element name="UTF16Length">
<short>
Gets the length for the specified value in UTF-16 characters.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>UTF16Length</var> is an overloaded <var>PtrInt</var> function used to get 
the length for the specified value as a number of Unicode code points. The 
overloaded variants allow the string examined in the routine to be specified 
as either a <var>UnicodeString</var> or a <var>PWideChar</var> type. The 
variant using PWideChar includes the WordCount argument with the number of 
Word values in the input.
</p>
<p>
UTF16Length examines the input values to determine the number of code points 
for the return value. Each code point can be represented as either 1 or 2 word 
values in UTF-16. The UTF16CharacterLength routine is called for the input 
until the number of Word values has been examined in the method. The return 
value is incremented by 1 for each code point read from the input value.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="UTF16CharacterLength"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Length.Result">
<short>
Number of UTF-16 codepoints in the examined value.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Length.s">
<short>
Unicode string with the values examined in the routine.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Length.p">
<short>
Pointer to the WideChar values examined in the routine.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Length.WordCount">
<short>
Number of UTF-16 word values to examine in the Unicode string.
</short>
</element>

<element name="UTF16Copy">
<short>
Copies a number of UTF-16 characters at the given character position in the 
specified value.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Copy.Result">
<short>UnicodeString with the values copied in the routine.</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Copy.s">
<short>UnicodeString with the values examined in the routine.</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Copy.StartCharIndex">
<short>
1-based staring character (code point) position in the Unicode string.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Copy.CharCount">
<short>Number of characters (code points) copied in the routine.</short>
</element>

<element name="UTF16CharStart">
<short>
Gets a pointer to the Unicode character at the ordinal position in P specified 
by the CharIndex argument.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>P</var> is the <var>PWideChar</var> value with the content examined in 
the routine.
</p>
<p>
<var>Len</var> contains the number of <var>Word</var> values examined in the P 
argument.
</p>
<p>
<var>CharIndex</var> specifies the ordinal position in P for the character 
pointer in the return value. CharIndex is zero-based and refers to a code 
point in P and not the individual Word values.
</p>
<p>
UTF16CharStart calls the <var>UTF16CharacterLength</var> routine to examine 
and skip each of the code points in P until the code point at CharIndex is 
found. The return value points to the Unicode character at the specified 
ordinal position. The return value is Nil for any of the following conditions:
</p>
<ul>
<li>The P argument is <b>Nil</b>.</li>
<li>Len is zero or a negative number.</li>
<li>The code point at CharIndex does not exist in the specified Len.</li>
</ul>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="UTF16CharacterLength"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="UTF16CharStart.Result">
<short>
Pointer to the Unicode character (code point) at the specified ordinal 
position.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16CharStart.P">
<short>PWideChar value with the values examined in the routine.</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16CharStart.Len">
<short>Len is the number of Word values in P.</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16CharStart.CharIndex">
<short>
CharIndex is the position for the desired UnicodeChar (starting at 0).
</short>
</element>

<element name="UTF16Pos">
<short>Pos implemented for UTF-16-encoded values.</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>UTF16Pos</var> is a <var>PtrInt</var> function used to get the character
index in SearchInText where the value in SearchForText is located. StartPos
allows the search to begin at a specific character (code point).
</p>
<p>
The return value is the 1-based UTF-16 character index where the SearchForText
starts in SearchInText, or 0 when not found.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Pos.Result">
<short>
Character index where the SearchForText starts in SearchInText, or 0 when not 
found.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Pos.SearchForText">
<short>UTF-16-encoded value to locate in SearchInText.</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Pos.SearchInText">
<short>UTF-16-encoded value searched in the routine.</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16Pos.StartPos">
<short>
Optional starting position (in UTF-16 code points, not in words).
</short>
</element>

<element name="UTF16CharacterToUnicode">
<short>
Converts ordinal values for UTF-16 code points in p to its Unicode equivalent.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
UTF16CharacterToUnicode converts 16-bit values in p to the equivalent Unicode 
value.
</p>
<p>
Unpaired surrogates are invalid in any UTFs. These include any value in the 
range $D800..$DBFF not followed by a value in the range $DC00..$DFFF, or any 
value in the range $DC00..$DFFF not preceded by a value in the range 
$D800..$DBFF.
</p>
<p>
UTF16CharacterToUnicode ensures that ordinal value(s) in the reserved 
range(s) are converted to the correct Unicode value. CharLen is updated to 
reflect whether the values in p are a character represented by a single 
UTF-16 code point (1), or requires 2 code points for the surrogate pair (2). 
It is set to 0 when p contains an invalid UTF-16 code point.
</p>
<p>
The return value contains the Cardinal value for the Unicode code point, or 0 
when p contains an invalid UTF-16 code point.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="UTF16CharacterToUnicode.Result">
<short>Unicode code point for the values in p.</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16CharacterToUnicode.p">
<short>UTF-16 code points examined and converted in the routine.</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF16CharacterToUnicode.CharLen">
<short>Number of UTF-16 code points for the converted character.</short>
</element>

<element name="UnicodeToUTF16">
<short>
Converts a Unicode character (code point) to its UTF-16 equivalent as a UnicodeString type.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Cardinal values below $10000 result in a single WideChar value for the code 
point.  Cardinal values in the range $D800 - $DFFF are reserved code points 
and contain 2 WideChar values in the result to represent the UTF-16 code 
point. WIdeChar values are cast to the UnicodeString type used in the return 
value.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="UnicodeToUTF16.Result">
<short>
UnicodeString value for the specified UTF-16 code point.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UnicodeToUTF16.u">
<short>
Cardinal value with the UTF-16 code point converted in the routine.
</short>
</element>

<element name="IsUTF16CharValid">
<short>
Returns <b>True</b> if the specified values are a valid UTF-16 character 
(codepoint).
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Based on the specification defined by the Unicode consortium, at:
</p>
<p>
<url href="https://unicode.org/faq/utf_bom.html#utf16-7">
https://unicode.org/faq/utf_bom.html#utf16-7
</url>
</p>
<p>
Q: Are there any 16-bit values that are invalid?
</p>
<p>
A: Unpaired surrogates are invalid in UTFs. These include any value in the
range D800 to DBFF not followed by a value in the range DC00 to DFFF, or
any value in the range DC00 to DFFF not preceded by a value in the range
D800 to DBFF. [AF]
</p>
<p>
If ANextChar is set to #0 there is no next character.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="IsUTF16CharValid.Result">
<short>
Returns False if AChar is #0 or AChar and ANextChar are unpaired surrogates.
</short>
</element>
<element name="IsUTF16CharValid.AChar">
<short>
First UTF-16 code examined in the method.
</short>
</element>
<element name="IsUTF16CharValid.ANextChar">
<short>
Next UTF-16 code examined in the method.
</short>
</element>

<element name="IsUTF16StringValid">
<short>
Determines if the specified Unicode string contains valid UTF-16 code points.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Examines the content in AStr for valid UTF-16 characters. Calls IsUTF16CharValid for consecutive code point pairs.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="IsUTF16StringValid.Result">
<short>
<b>True</b> if the specified Unicode string contains valid UTF-16 code points.
</short>
</element>
<element name="IsUTF16StringValid.AWideStr">
<short>
Unicode string examined in the routine.
</short>
</element>

<element name="Utf16StringReplace">
<short>
Replaces a pattern in a Unicode string with another Unicode pattern.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Same as <var>SysUtil.StringReplace</var> but for WideStrings and 
UnicodeStrings, since it is not available in FPC yet.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="#rtl.sysutils.StringReplace">StringReplace</link>
<link id="#rtl.sysutils.TReplaceFlags">TReplaceFlags</link>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="Utf16StringReplace.Result">
<short>
Updated value for Unicode string after pattern replacement(s).
</short>
</element>
<element name="Utf16StringReplace.S">
<short>
Unicode string value examined in the routine.
</short>
</element>
<element name="Utf16StringReplace.OldPattern">
<short>
Unicode string with the pattern to locate in S.
</short>
</element>
<element name="Utf16StringReplace.NewPattern">
<short>
Unicode string with the pattern used to replace the old pattern in S.
</short>
</element>
<element name="Utf16StringReplace.Flags">
<short>
Set of replacement flags applied in the routine.
</short>
</element>
<element name="Utf16StringReplace.Count">
<short>
Number of replacements performed in the routine.
</short>
</element>

<element name="UnicodeLowercase">
<short>
Converts the specified Unicode (UTF-16) codepoint to its lowercase equivalent.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>UnicodeLowercase</var> ensures the character (16-bit codepoint) is 
converted to lowercase using the case conversion logic for the UTF-16 encoding. 
Characters in the following Unicode blocks are handled:
</p>
<dl>
<dt>$0041..$005A</dt>
<dd>Capital letters in the C0 Latin block</dd>
<dt>$00C0..$00DE</dt>
<dd>Capital letters in the C1 Latin-1 Supplement block</dd>
<dt>$0100..$024E</dt>
<dd>Capital letters in the Latin Extended-A block</dd>
<dt>$0386..$03AB</dt>
<dd>Capital letters in the Greek and Coptic block</dd>
<dt>$03D8..$042F</dt>
<dd>Archaic letters in the Greek and Coptic block</dd>
<dt>$0460..$0512</dt>
<dd>Historic letters in Cyrillic block</dd>
<dt>$0531..$0556</dt>
<dd>Capital letters in the Armenian block</dd>
<dt>$10A0..$10C5</dt>
<dd>Capital letters in the Georgian block</dd>
<dt>$1E00..$1FFC</dt>
<dd>Capital letters in the Latin Extended Additional block</dd>
<dt>$2126..$2183</dt>
<dd>Characters in the Letter-like Symbols block</dd>
<dt>$24B6..$24CF</dt>
<dd>Parenthesized Latin letters in the Enclosed Alphanumerics block</dd>
<dt>$2C00..$2C2E</dt>
<dd>Capital letters in the Glagolitic block (precursor of Cyrillic)</dd>
<dt>$2C60..$2CE2</dt>
<dd>Capital letters in the Latin Extended-C block</dd>
<dt>$FF21..$FF3A</dt>
<dd>ASCII variants in the Halfwidth and Fullwidth Forms block</dd>
</dl>
</descr>
<version>
Modified in LazUtils version 4.0 to dynamically initialize the character 
mapping tables once when either UnicodeLowercase or UTF8LowerCaseViaTables is 
called.
</version>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="UnicodeLowercase.Result">
<short>
Cardinal value with the lowercase equivalent for <var>u</var>, or the value in 
<var>u</var> when conversion is not needed.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UnicodeLowercase.u">
<short>
Cardinal value for the Unicode character converted to lowercase in the routine.
</short>
</element>

<element name="UTF8LowerCaseViaTables">
<short>
Converts a UTF-8-encoded string to lowercase UTF-8 values using internal 
case tables.
</short>
<descr/>
<version>
Modified in LazUtils version 4.0 to dynamically initialize the character 
mapping tables once when either UnicodeLowercase or UTF8LowerCaseViaTables is 
called.
</version>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="UTF8LowerCaseViaTables.Result">
<short>String with the lowercase UTF-8 values for s.</short>
</element>
<element name="UTF8LowerCaseViaTables.s">
<short>
String with UTF-8 values converted to lowercase UTF-8 in the routine.
</short>
</element>

</module>
<!-- lazutf16 -->
</package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
