<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--

Documentation for LCL (Lazarus Component Library) and LazUtils (Lazarus 
Utilities) are published under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 
International public license.

https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/legalcode.txt
https://gitlab.com/freepascal.org/lazarus/lazarus/-/blob/main/docs/cc-by-sa-4-0.txt

Copyright (c) 1997-2024, by the Lazarus Development Team.

-->
<fpdoc-descriptions>
<package name="lazutils">
<!--
====================================================================
Translations
====================================================================
-->
<module name="Translations">
<short>
Contains classes and routines used to load/check/maintain translations from 
.po (portable object) files.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<file>translations.pas</file> contains classes and routines used to 
load/check/maintain translations from .po (portable object) files.
</p>
<p>
<file>translations.pas</file> is part of the <file>LazUtils</file> package.
</p>
<p>
Initial authors: Mattias Gaertner, Bart Broersma, Giuliano Colla
</p>
<p>
<b>Example 1</b>: Load a specific .po file
</p>
<code>
  procedure TForm1.FormCreate(Sender: TObject);
  var
    PODirectory: String;
  begin
    PODirectory := '/path/to/lazarus/lcl/languages/';
    TranslateUnitResourceStrings('LCLStrConsts',
      PODirectory+'lcl.%s.po', 'nl', '');
    MessageDlg('Title', 'Text', mtInformation, [mbOk, mbCancel, mbYes], 0);
  end;
</code>
<p>
<b>Example 2</b>: Load the current language file using the GetLanguageID 
function:
</p>
<code>
uses
 ...
 Translations;

  procedure TranslateLCL;
  var
    PODirectory: String;
    LangID: TLanguageID;  
  begin
    PODirectory:='/path/to/lazarus/lcl/languages/';
    LangID := GetLanguageID;
    Translations.TranslateUnitResourceStrings('LCLStrConsts',
      PODirectory+'lclstrconsts.%s.po', LangID.LanguageID, 
      LangID.LanguageCode);
  end;
  ...
begin
  TranslateLCL;
  Application.Initialize;
  Application.CreateForm(TForm1, Form1);
  Application.Run;
end.
</code>
</descr>

<!-- unresolved references -->
<element name="Classes"/>
<element name="SysUtils"/>
<element name="jsonscanner"/>
<element name="jsonparser"/>
<element name="fpjson"/>
<element name="FileUtil"/>
<element name="LazFileUtils"/>
<element name="LazUTF8"/>
<element name="LConvEncoding"/>
<element name="LazLoggerBase"/>
<element name="AvgLvlTree"/>
<element name="StringHashList"/>

<element name="TLanguageID">
<short>
Record type used to return language and country codes/identifiers for a 
locale.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
TLanguageID is the type returned from the GetLanguageID function.
</p>
</descr>
<version>
Added in LazUtils version 3.0.
</version>
<seealso>
<link id="GetLanguageID"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TLanguageID.LanguageID">
<short>
Language ID is the combined values for the LanguageCode and CountryCode 
members. For example: 'en_US'.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TLanguageID.LanguageCode">
<short>
ISO 639-1 or 639-2 language code. For example: 'en' or 'eng'.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TLanguageID.CountryCode">
<short>
ISO 3166 country code. For example: 'US' or 'USA'.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TStringsType">
<short>
Format used in the string table passed to the TPOFile.UpdateStrings method.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Determines the inner method called to process values passed in the argument.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.UpdateStrings"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TStringsType.stLrj">
<short>Lazarus resource string table in JSON format.</short>
</element>
<element name="TStringsType.stRst">
<short>FPC resource string table (prior to FPC 2.7.1).</short>
</element>
<element name="TStringsType.stRsj">
<short>FPC resource string table in JSON format (since FPC 2.7.1).</short>
</element>

<element name="GetLanguageID">
<short>
Gets a record with the language code and country code for the current system 
locale.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>GetLanguageID</var> is a <var>TLanguageID</var> function which returns a 
record with language code (in ISO 639-1 or ISO 639-2) and country code (in ISO 
3166) for the current system locale. The implementation is based on 
GetLanguageIDs procedure from the GetText unit, but is rewritten to have the 
following properties:
</p>
<ol>
<li>
Language and country codes are returned in ISO formats on Windows.
</li>
<li>
A Unix locale identifier is properly parsed and language/country codes are 
properly extracted.
</li>
<li>
Don't assume that language code is always two-letters (ISO 639-1), it can have 
a bigger length (e. g. three letters, like in ISO 639-2).
</li>
<li>
Provides support for locale information on Darwin platforms. macOS does not 
set language environment variables for GUI applications which are not started 
from a terminal. This routine ensures that locale information is available for 
both console applications and GUI applications, independent of environment 
variables like LC_ALL / LC_MESSAGES / LANG, or Application bundle settings. The 
locale information uses ISO formats like `ru_RU`, `zh_CN`, or `it_IT`.
</li>
<li>
Returns the locale information in a record type. This allows additional fields 
in a backwards-compatible manner. Currently it contains language ID, language 
code and country code.
</li>
</ol>
<p>
GetLanguageID is used in the implementation of routines in the 
<file>lcltranslator.pas</file> unit, and can be called by other components 
and classes which use the localization feature.
</p>
</descr>
<version>
Added in LazUtils version 3.0.
</version>
<seealso>
<link id="TLanguageID"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="GetLanguageID.Result">
<short>
TLanguageID instance with the language identifier and country code for the 
current locale.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TTranslateUnitResult">
<short>
Represents the return value for the TranslateUnitResourceStrings function.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>TTranslateUnitResult</var> is an enumeration type with values that can be 
returned from the overloaded TranslateUnitResourceStrings function.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TranslateUnitResourceStrings"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TTranslateUnitResult.turOK">
<short>
Resources were successfully translated.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TTranslateUnitResult.turNoLang">
<short>
The language identifier was omitted or a .po file for the language was not 
found .
</short>
</element>
<element name="TTranslateUnitResult.turNoFBLang">
<short>
The fallback language identifier was omitted or a .po file for the language 
was not found.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TTranslateUnitResult.turEmptyParam">
<short>
The unit file name or the base file name argument was not specified.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TTranslationStatistics">
<short>
Represents translation statistics calculated for the key/value pairs in a .po translation file.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>TTranslationStatistics</var> is the type used to implement the statistics 
property in <var>TPOFile</var>. It contains information about the key/value 
pairs in the .po (Portable Object) file such as: successful translations, 
untranslated item count, and number of entries with the "fuzzy" keyword for 
unverified translations.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.Statistics"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TTranslationStatistics.Translated">
<short>
Number of keys with a valid localized value.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TTranslationStatistics.Untranslated">
<short>
Number of keys with no localized value.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TTranslationStatistics.Fuzzy">
<short>
Number of keys with the "fuzzy" keyword indicating an unverified localized 
value.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem">
<short>
Represents a single key/value pair in a .po file which maps a string to its 
translated value.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>TPOFileItem</var> is a class used to represent a key/value pair defined 
in a .po (Portable Object) file. It provides members, properties, and methods 
used to process, store, and maintain a single translation defined in a .po 
file.
</p>
<p>
TPOFileItem is the type used for the POItems property in TPOFile. It is also 
passed as an argument or used as the return value for methods in TPOFile.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
<link id="TPOFile.ReadPOText"/>
<link id="TPOFile.FillItem"/>
<link id="TPOFile.UpdateItem"/>
<link id="TPOFile.Remove"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- private -->
<element name="TPOFileItem.FInitialFuzzyState"/>
<element name="TPOFileItem.FVirtualTranslation"/>

<!-- public -->
<element name="TPOFileItem.Tag">
<short>
Arbitrary value which can be used to identify the translation entry.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Tag</var> is a public <var>Integer</var> member which contains an 
arbitrary value used to locate or maintain the translation entry. Tag is used 
in TPOFile methods like UntagAll and RemoveTaggedItems, and in the 
UpdatePOFile routine.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.Tag"/>
<link id="TPOFile.UntagAll"/>
<link id="TPOFile.RemoveTaggedItems"/>
<link id="UpdatePOFile"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.LineNr">
<short>
Line number in a .po file where the first line for the translation entry was 
found.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.ReadPOText"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.Comments">
<short>
Contains the comments with the notes for translators, flag values, et. al. for 
the translation entry.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Comments</var> is a public <var>String</var> member which contains the 
comment lines which occur at the start of the translation entry. It is an 
empty string ('') if no comments were found prior to the key/value pair in 
Original and Translation. If multiple comment lines (starting with the '#' 
character) are found, and line ending sequence is added at the end of each 
comment.
</p>
<p>
The value in Comments is detected when the ReadPOText method in TPOFile is 
called to process the contents of a .po file, and stored when the FillItem 
method in TPOFile is called.
</p>
<p>
A comment line starts with the # character and relates to the first 
entry after the comment. Comment types and uses are defined as follows:
</p>
<dl>
<dt>'# '</dt>
<dd>
Contains a note for translators. Normally, this is the only comment that is
manually written.
</dd>
<dt>'#.''</dt>
<dd>
Comment was extracted from the source code with the Gettext tool.
</dd>
<dt>'#:''</dt>
<dd>
Contains a reference to the source code with the message ids translated using 
the file. A Colon (':') is used as a delimiter between distinct values in the 
reference. For instance: '#: lazarusidestrconsts:lisdonotshowsplashscreen:224'.
</dd>
<dt>#, fuzzy, object-pascal-format, no-object-pascal-format, badformat</dt>
<dd>
<p>
Flag values from the translator or the Gettext tool. Unlike other comments, 
these lines may be handled or applied in the application. The comma-delimited 
list of flags may be used to apply the translation based on the comment type.
</p>
<p>
"fuzzy" is inserted by a translator when the translated value might not be a 
correct translation. When verified, the "fuzzy" attribute can be removed in 
the .po file. A translation with the "fuzzy" flag is not applied in the 
application.
</p>
<p>
"badformat" indicates the message ID or translated value has an invalid 
format. A translation with the "badformat" flag is not applied in the 
application.
</p>
<p>
"object-pascal-format" and "no-object-pascal-format"indicate that the message 
ID or translated value does or does not use the format for the Object Pascal 
language. These are generated by automated PO processing tools.
</p>
</dd>
<dt>#|</dt>
<dd>
Represents the previous (older) msgid, msgstr, or msgctxt value for the 
message ID which follows the comment.
</dd>
</dl>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.IdentifierLow">
<short>
Lowercase variant of the message identifier or untranslated value.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFileItem.Original"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem.Translation"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.Original">
<short>
Original untranslated value prior to localization using the value in 
Translation.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFileItem.IdentifierLow"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem.Translation"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.Translation">
<short>
Translated or localized value for the message identifier.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.Flags">
<short>
Comma-delimited list of Flag names found in the comments for the translation 
entry.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.PreviousID">
<short>
Prior message ID used for the value in Original.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.Context">
<short>
Contains the msgctxt (message context) for the key/value pair.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Context</var> provides a context used differentiate identifiers with the 
same untranslated value. Please note that an empty context string ("") and an 
absent msgctxt line do not mean the same thing.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.Duplicate">
<short>
Indicates if the key/value pair is a duplicate of a previous entry.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.Create">
<short>
Constructor for the class instance.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Create</var> stores the values passed as arguments to the method to the 
members in the class instance. It also initializes internal members used in 
the class instance.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFileItem.Create.TheIdentifierLow">
<short>
Lowercase value for the message identifier (msgid).
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFileItem.Create.TheOriginal">
<short>
The original untranslated value for the message identifier.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFileItem.Create.TheTranslated">
<short>
Translated value (msgstr) for the message identifier.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.ModifyFlag">
<short>
Examines and updates the Flags property for the specified values.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFileItem.ModifyFlag.Result">
<short>
<b>True</b> if the Flags property has been modified in the method.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFileItem.ModifyFlag.AFlags">
<short>
Comma-delimited list of flags accepted in the method.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFileItem.ModifyFlag.Check">
<short>
<b>True</b> causes an existing flag value to be removed. <b>False</b> causes a 
missing flag value to be added.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.InitialFuzzyState">
<short>
Indicates whether the translation entry is marked with the "fuzzy" state comment.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>InitialFuzzyState</var> is a read-only <var>Boolean</var> property which 
indicates if the key/value pair was marked with the "fuzzy" comment in the .po 
file. The default value for the property is <b>False</b>. It is used when 
generating translation statistics when the .po file is processed.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFileItem.VirtualTranslation">
<short>
Indicates whether the translation is included in statistics generated when a 
.po file is processed and applied.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>VirtualTranslation</var> is a read-only Boolean property which indicates 
whether the translation entry had an actual value in its identifier and 
translated value. The default value for the property is <b>False</b>. 
<b>True</b> indicates that both msgid and msgstr were empty, per the 
convention used for a .po file header. Translations entries which are virtual 
are not included in the translation statistics.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile">
<short>
Class used to represent a .po file with translation entries for a single 
target language.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>TPOFile</var> is a class which provides access to a file with translation 
entries used to localize a source file to the language or locale defined in a 
.po (Portable Object) file. .po files are part of the GNU gettext tool set 
used to produce and update translation files. Information about the .po file 
format can be found at:
</p>
<p>
<url href="https://www.gnu.org/software/gettext/manual/html_node/PO-Files.html">The Format of PO Files</url>
</p>
<p>
TPOFile provides properties and methods used to load and save translation 
entries using a file, stream, or resource. The Header property contains the 
header information for the .po file, and may contain information about: the 
MIME version and content transfer encoding, target language, plural forms, and 
generation tools. Use the POItems property to access the translation entries 
defined in the .po file.
</p>
<p>
TPOFile also provides Statistics about the translations applied to a source 
file when the Translate method is called.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFileItem"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<!-- private -->
<element name="TPOFile.FStatisticsUpdated"/>
<element name="TPOFile.FStatistics"/>
<element name="TPOFile.GetStatistics"/>
<element name="TPOFile.GetStatistics.Result"/>

<!-- protected -->
<element name="TPOFile.FItems">
<short>
Member with the list of TPOFileItem instances in POItems.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FIdentifierLowToItem">
<short>
Member with the lowercase identifier to TPOFileItem mapping.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FOriginalToItem">
<short>
Member with the original value to TPOFileItem mapping.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FCharSet">
<short>
Member with the value for the CharSet property. 
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FHeader">
<short>
Member with the value for the Header property.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FAllEntries">
<short>
Member with the scope for the translations applied from the .po file.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FTag">
<short>
Member with the value for the Tag property.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FModified">
<short>
Member with the value for the Modified property.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FHelperList">
<short>
Member with the string list used to convert the .po file in the SaveToStrings 
method.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FPoName">
<short>
Member with the value for the POName and PORename properties.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Remove">
<short>
Gets the translation entry at the specified ordinal position in POItems and 
removes it from the list.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Remove.Index">
<short>
Ordinal position in POItems for the translation entry removed in the method.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Remove.Result">
<short>
TPOFileItem removed from the list.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.GetCount">
<short>
Gets the value for the Count property.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.Count"/>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.GetCount.Result">
<short>
Value for the Count property.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.SetCharSet">
<short>
Updates the value in the CharSet property.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>SetCharSet</var> ensures that <var>CharSet</var> contains 'UTF-8' when an 
empty value ('') is passed in the <var>AValue</var> argument. Please note that 
SetCharSet is <b>not</b> the write access specifier for the CharSet property; 
CharSet is defined as read-only.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.SetCharSet.AValue">
<short>
New value for the CharSet property.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.GetPoItem">
<short>
Gets the value for the indexed POItems property.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.GetPoItem.Result">
<short>
Value for the indexed POItems property.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.GetPoItem.Index">
<short>
Ordinal position for the TPOFileItem instance used as the property value.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.ReadPOText">
<short>
Reads the content for the .po file from the specified source.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>ReadPOText</var> is an overloaded method used to load translation entries 
from the specified source into the class instance. The overloaded variants 
allow the .po content to be loaded from a TStream instance or a String.
</p>
<p>
The TStream-based variant stores the content starting at the current stream 
position to a String value. The String-based variant is called examine and 
process the values. The stream position is not reset before or after reading 
values from the stream.
</p>
<p>
The String-based variant reads lines of text from the Txt argument and 
performs actions to create and populate the POItems in the class instance. 
It accounts for both the header in the .po file and the comment lines which 
occur prior to a translation entry. Values for message Identifiers (msgid), 
translations (msgstr), and Contexts (msgctxt) are handled in the method. If 
the file header indicates that a content encoding other than UTF-8 is used in 
the .po file, its content is transcoded by calling ConvertEncoding.
</p>
<p>
Use SavetoStrings or SaveToFile to store updated values in the class instance.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.ReadPOText.AStream">
<short>
TStream instance with the translation entries for the .po file.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.ReadPOText.Txt">
<short>
String with the translation entries for the .po file.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Create">
<short>
Constructor for the class instance.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Create</var> is the overloaded constructor for the class instance. The 
overloaded variants allow the class to be created and populated from a 
TStream, a .po file, or uninitialized for use with an internal resource.
</p>
<p>
Create allocates resources needed in the class instance, and sets the default 
values for its members.
</p>
<p>
For the variant with the AFilename argument, a TFileStream instance is created 
for use in the overloaded Create method. The CreateHeader method is called if 
a value has not been assigned to the Header property.
</p>
<p>
The stream-based variant is used to load values from the TStream argument. The 
ReadPOText method is called to load, process, and apply the translation 
entries found in the .po file.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.POName"/>
<link id="TPOFile.Header"/>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
<link id="TPOFile.ReadPOText"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Create.Full">
<short>
Use <b>False</b> when loading from an internal resource. Default is 
<b>True</b>.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Create.AFilename">
<short>
Name for the .po file loaded into the class instance.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Create.AStream">
<short>
TStream instance with the translation entries loaded in the method.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Destroy">
<short>
Destructor for the class instance.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Translate">
<short>
Retrieves the translation entry for the specified identifier and returns the 
translated value.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Translate</var> is a method used to retrieve the translation entry for a 
given identifier, and return the translated value for the 
<var>TPOFileItem</var>.
</p>
<p>
<var>Identifier</var> contains the msgid for the translation entry.
</p>
<p>
<var>OriginalValue</var> contains the untranslated value for the Identifier.
</p>
<p>
A translation is loaded only when it exists, and does not include 'fuzzy' or 
'badformat' in its flag values. This is done to mimic gettext behavior and to 
avoid crashes related to formatting argument mismatches.
</p>
<p>
The return value contains the Translation property for the TPOFileItem when 
found. When not found, the value in the Original property is used. If the 
translated value is an empty string (''), the untranslated value in 
OriginalValue is used as the return value for the method.
</p>
<p>
Translate is called from the implementation routine used in the 
TranslateUnitResourceStrings routine.
</p>
</descr>
<errors>
Raises an exception with the message 'TPOFile.Translate Inconsistency' if a 
translation is not found (or created) for the Identifier, or the flags for the 
translation include 'fuzzy' or 'badformat'.
</errors>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Translate.Result">
<short>
Translated value for the identifier, or the original value if a translation 
cannot be located or used.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Translate.Identifier">
<short>
Identifier (msgid) for the translation entry used in the method.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Translate.OriginalValue">
<short>
Original untranslated value for the specified Identifier.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.CharSet">
<short>
Character set used for the contents of the .po file.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>CharSet</var> is a read-only <var>String</var> property which contains 
the character set encoding used in the .po file or stream. Its value is 
captured from the 'content-type' header included in the .po file. If omitted 
in the .po file, the value 'UTF-8' is used. When CharSet is set to a value 
other than 'UTF-8', the ConvertEncoding routine is called to transcode the 
content in the .po file to UTF-8.
</p>
<p>
Use SetCharSet to manually override the character set used for the translation 
entries in the class instance.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Report">
<short>
Generates output with the values in the Header and the translation entries in 
the .po file.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Report</var> is an overloaded method in <var>TPOFile</var> used to 
generate output with the values from the Header and the POItems translation 
entries for the .po file. The overloaded variants allow the output to be sent 
to the DebugLn routine or stored in a TStrings instance.
</p>
<p>
Use <var>DisplayHeader</var> to control whether values in the Header section 
of the .po file are included the output for the report.
</p>
<p>
Use <var>StartIndex</var> and <var>StopIndex</var> to specify a range of 
translation entries found in POItems in the output for the report.
</p>
<p>
The variant with the <var>Log</var> parameter allows the output to be stored 
in the TString instance passed in the argument.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Report.StartIndex">
<short>
Ordinal position for the first translation entry included in the output.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Report.StopIndex">
<short>
Ordinal position for the last translation entry included in the output.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Report.DisplayHeader">
<short>
<b>True</b> to display values found the Header for the .po file.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.Report.Log">
<short>
TStrings instance where the output for the report is stored.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.CreateHeader">
<short>
Ensures that a TPOFileItem instance is allocated for the Header property 
(when not already assigned).
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>CreateHeader</var> sets the value for the Translation property in Header 
to the default content type for the .po file: 
</p>
<code>
'Content-Type: text/plain; charset=UTF-8'.
</code>
<p>
CreateHeader is called from the file-based variant of the Create constructor, 
and from the SaveToStrings method when Header has not been assigned.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.Header"/>
<link id="TPOFile.CharSet"/>
<link id="TPOFile.Create"/>
<link id="TPOFile.SaveToStrings"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem.Translation"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem.Comments"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.UpdateStrings">
<short>
Adds or updates translation entries in POItems using the values specified in 
InputLines.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>UpdateStrings</var> is a method used to refresh the translation entries 
in the .po file from the values specified in the <var>InputLines</var> 
argument. Values in InputLines are stored using the format specified in the 
<var>SType</var> argument, and includes:
</p>
<dl>
<dt>stLrj</dt>
<dd>
Lazarus resource string table in JSON format
</dd>
<dt>stRst</dt>
<dd>
FPC resource string table (before FPC 2.7.1)
</dd>
<dt>stRsj</dt>
<dd>
FPC resource string table in JSON format (since FPC 2.7.1)
</dd>
</dl>
<p>
UpdateStrings provides nested routines used to read the various formats and to 
apply the translation entries to POItems. Each identifier and value are read 
from InputLines and UpdateItem is called to store the data. 
</p>
<p>
UpdateStrings is used in the implementation of the UpdatePOFile routine.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
<link id="TPOFile.Items"/>
<link id="TPOFile.UpdateItem"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem"/>
<link id="TStringsType"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.UpdateStrings.InputLines">
<short>
TStrings instance with the translation entries stored in the .po file class 
instance.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.UpdateStrings.SType">
<short>
Identifies the format for the identifiers and values in the InputLines 
argument.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.SaveToStrings">
<short>
Stores values from Header and the sorted POItems to the specified string list.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>SaveToStrings</var> is a method used to store values from the .po file 
class instance to the TStrings instance in <var>OutLst</var>. Values in the 
Header and POItems properties are stored in OutLst.
</p>
<p>
SaveToStrings calls CreateHeader to ensure that the Header property has been 
allocated for the class instance. Values in POItems are sorted (without case 
sensitivity) in Identifier order prior to storing the values in OutLst.
</p>
<p>
Values written to OutLst are stored in the PO (Portable Object) format used by 
the GNU gettext localization library. The following properties from the 
TPOFileItem entries in Items are stored:
</p>
<dl>
<dt>Comments</dt>
<dd>
Stored with the '# ' prefix but not quoted in any form.
</dd>
<dt>IdentifierLow</dt>
<dd>
Stored with the '#: ' prefix.
</dd>
<dt>Flags</dt>
<dd>
Stored with the '#, ' prefix.
</dd>
<dt>PreviousID</dt>
<dd>
Stored with the '#| msgid' prefix using escaped values for Quote (&quot;), 
Backslash (\), and Tab (#9) characters.
</dd>
<dt>Context</dt>
<dd>
Stored with the 'msgctxt' prefix.
</dd>
<dt>Original</dt>
<dd>
Stored with the 'msgid' prefix using escaped values for Quote (&quot;), 
Backslash (\), and Tab (#9) characters.
</dd>
<dt>Translation</dt>
<dd>
Stored with the 'msgstr' prefix using escaped values for Quote (&quot;), 
Backslash (\), and Tab (#9) characters.
</dd>
</dl>
<p>
Properties which have a blank value ('') are not stored in OutLst.
</p>
<p>
Use SaveToFile to store the contents of the .po file to a specified file name.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.SaveToStrings.OutLst">
<short>
TStrings instance where the header and translation entries in the class are 
stored.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.SaveToFile">
<short>
Stores values from Header and the sorted POItems to the specified file name.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>SaveToFile</var> is a method used to store the contents in the .po file 
class instance to the file name specified in the <var>AFilename</var> 
argument. AFilename contains an optional path and the file name and extension 
where the values are stored.
</p>
<p>
SaveToFile creates a temporary TStringList instance and calls the 
SaveToStrings method to populate the list with the Header and Items in the 
class instance. Its contents are stored to the location specified in 
AFilename. If AFilename already exists, it is overwritten.
</p>
<p>
Value are written to the file in the PO (Portable Object) format used by 
the GNU gettext localization library. See <link id="TPOFile.SaveToStrings">
SaveToStrings</link> for more information about the properties included in 
the output and their storage formats.
</p>
<p>
Use the overloaded Create variant with a file name argument to load a .po file 
class instance from a specified file using the .po format.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.SaveToStrings"/>
<link id="TPOFile.Header"/>
<link id="TPOFile.Items"/>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
<link id="TPOFile.Create"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.SaveToFile.AFilename">
<short>
Name of the file where the values in the .po file are stored.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.UpdateItem">
<short>
Adds or updates a translation entry which has the specified Identifier.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>UpdateItem</var> is a method used to update a translation entry in Items 
with the msgid specified in the <var>Identifier</var> argument. It stores the 
values from the Identifier, <var>Original</var>, and <var>Flags</var> 
arguments to the <var>TPOFileItem</var> instance. If a translation entry with 
the specified identifier is not found in Items (POItems), it is added.
</p>
<p>
The <var>ProcessingTranslation</var> argument indicates whether values in the 
Flags argument are synchronized to the values in the TPOFileItem instance. 
When set to <b>True</b>, the "fuzzy" flag value in the POItems entry is 
retained and merged with the new Flag values.
</p>
<p>
UpdateItem calls the FillItem method to validate and apply the updated 
translation entry to the TPOFileItem instance in Items.
</p>
<p>
UpdateItem is used in methods like UpdateStrings and UpdateTranslation in 
TPOFile.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.Items"/>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
<link id="TPOFile.FillItem"/>
<link id="TPOFile.UpdateStrings"/>
<link id="TPOFile.UpdateTranslation"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem.IdentifierLow"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem.Original"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem.Translation"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem.Flags"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.UpdateItem.Identifier">
<short>
Identifier (msgid) for the translation entry.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.UpdateItem.Original">
<short>
Untranslated value for the specified identifier.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.UpdateItem.Flags">
<short>
Optional comma-delimited list of flags for the translation entry.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.UpdateItem.ProcessingTranslation">
<b>True</b> if the translation entry is being synchronized with a base (.pot) 
file; updates translation flags but retains the fuzzy flag state. <b>False</b> 
if flags in a base (.pot) file are kept as is, but the item translation must 
be empty there.
<short>
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FillItem">
<short>
Stores argument values to the specified translation entry.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>FillItem</var> is a method used to store values passed in the specified 
arguments to the TPOFileItem instance in <var>CurrentItem</var>. If 
CurrentItem is <b>Nil</b>, a new TPOFileItem instance is created and used to 
stored the argument values. It is added to the Items in the class instance.
</p>
<p>
FillItem retrieves an existing TPOFileItem instance in Items and merges its 
properties into the values in CurrentItem. The value in CurrentItem is 
subsequently used to replace the translation entry in Items.
</p>
<p>
FillItem is used in methods like ReadPOText and UpdateItem in TPOFile.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FillItem.CurrentItem">
<short>
TPOFileItem instance where the argument values are stored.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FillItem.Identifier">
<short>
Identifier (msgid) for the translation entry.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FillItem.Original">
<short>
Untranslated value (msgstr) for the message identifier.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FillItem.Translation">
<short>
Translated value for the entry.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FillItem.Comments">
<short>
Comments for the translation entry.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FillItem.Context">
<short>
Context (msgctxt) for the translation entry.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FillItem.Flags">
<short>
Comma-delimited list of flag values for the translation entry.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FillItem.PreviousID">
<short>
Previous (older) message identifier for the translation entry.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FillItem.LineNr">
<short>
Line number in the .po file for the first line in the translation entry.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.UpdateTranslation">
<short>
Updates or removes translation entries in the .po file class based on the 
content in the specified .po file.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>UpdateTranslation</var> is a method used to update translation entries in 
Items from the translation entries in the specified <var>TPOFile</var> 
instance. UpdateTranslation resets the value in Tag to 0 (zero) for all of the 
POItems in the class instance. It visits each of the POItems in BasePOFile, 
and calls UpdateItem to apply the Original and Flags members to the entries in 
Items.
</p>
<p>
UpdateTranslation removes any entries in Items which do not exist in 
BasePOFile. InvalidateStatistics is called to reset the internal flag which 
indicates that translation statistics are up-to-date.
</p>
<p>
UpdateTranslation is called from the UpdatePoFileTranslations routine when a 
.pot template file has been provided in its arguments.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.UpdateTranslation.BasePOFile">
<short>
Name for the .po file with the translation entries applied to the Items in the 
class.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.UntagAll">
<short>
Resets the value in the Tag property for all of the translation entries in 
Items.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Iterates over the TPOFileItem instances in Items, and sets the value in each 
of the Tag properties to zero (0).
</p>
<p>
UntagAll is used in the UpdateTranslation method in TPOFile, and in the 
UpdatePOFile routine.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.RemoveTaggedItems">
<short>
Removes translation entries in POItems with the specified value in their Tag 
property.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
Visits the translation entries in Items in reverse order. It removes and frees 
each TPOFileItem instance in the Items list which has the specified value in 
its Tag member.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.RemoveTaggedItems.aTag">
<short>
Arbitrary numeric value for the tagged translations removed in the method.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.RemoveIdentifier">
<short>
Removes a translation entry in Items with the specified value in its 
identifier (msgid).
</short>
<descr>
<p>
No actions are performed in the method if AIdentifier is an empty string ('').
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.RemoveIdentifier.AIdentifier">
<short>
Identifier for the translation entry located and removed in the method.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.RemoveOriginal">
<short>
Removes a translation entry in POItems with has the specified value as its 
Original untranslated value.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>RemoveOriginal</var> visits each of the TPOFileItem instances in Items in 
reverse order. It removes the translation entry if the value in AOriginal is 
found in the multi-line value for the Original member in the TPOFileItem 
instance.
</p>
<p>
No actions are performed in the method if AOriginal is an empty string ('').
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.RemoveOriginal.AOriginal">
<short>
Untranslated value to locate and remove in the method.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.RemoveIdentifiers">
<short>
Removes translation entries from Items which have the identifiers (msgids) in 
the specified string list.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>RemoveIdentifiers</var> is a method used to remove translation entries in 
Items which have an identifier found in the <var>AIdentifiers</var> argument. 
</p>
<p>
AIdentifiers is a TStrings instance which contains one or more identifiers to 
be removed in the method. Each identifier should be a separate line of text in 
the TStrings instance.
</p>
<p>
RemoveIdentifiers iterates over the lines of text in AIdentifiers and calls 
the RemoveIdentifier method for the identifier value.
</p>
<p>
No actions are performed in the method if the Count property in AIdentifiers 
is 0 (zero).
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.RemoveIdentifiers.AIdentifiers">
<short>
TStrings instance with the identifiers located and removed in the method.
</short>
</element>

<!-- HERE -->
<element name="TPOFile.RemoveOriginals">
<short>
Removes translation entries from Items which have the original untranslated 
values in the specified string list.
</short>
<descr>

<p>
No actions are performed in the method when the Count property in AOriginals 
is zero (0).
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.RemoveOriginals.AOriginals">
<short>
TStrings instance with the untranslated values for translation entries removed 
in the method.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Tag">
<short>
Arbitrary value used to identify the .po file and its associated translation 
entries.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.RemoveTaggedItems"/>
<link id="TPOFile.UntagAll"/>
<link id="UpdatePOFile"/>
<link id="UpdatePOFileTranslations"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Modified">
<short>
Indicates whether values in the class instance have been modified since they 
were loaded from a .po file or stream.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Items">
<short>
Provides access to the TFPList instance where translation entries are stored.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Items</var> is a read-only <var>TFPList</var> property with the container 
where translation entries are stored in the class instance. Each translation 
entry is stored as an object instance in the container, and must be cast to a 
<var>TPOFileItem</var> instance to access properties and methods specific to 
the type.
</p>
<p>
Items allows access to the properties and methods in the TFPList instance, 
such as: Add, Delete, Move, Remove, IndexOf, First, Last, and Count. They are 
used in the implementation of TPOFile methods which maintain the translation 
entries like: UpdateItem, FillItem, RemoveIdentifier, RemoveOriginal , et. al.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem"/>
<link id="#rtl.classes.TFPList">TFPList</link>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.PoName">
<short>
Name for the .po file loaded into the class instance.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>POName</var> is a read-only <var>String</var> property with the name for 
the .po file loaded into the class instance. The property value is assigned in 
the Create constructor using the AFilename argument value passed to the method.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.Create"/>
<link id="TPOFile.PORename"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.PoRename">
<short>
Name for the .po file loaded into the class instance.
</short>
<descr/>
<notes><note>???</note></notes>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Statistics">
<short>
Provides access to statistics for the translation entries in the .po file.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Statistics</var> is a read-only <var>TTranslationStatistics</var> 
property with information about the translation entries in the POItems 
property. The statistics reflect the number of entries with a translated 
value, without a translated value (blank), and those which cannot be used due 
to use of "fuzzy" or "badformat" flags in the translation.
</p>
<p>
An internal flag is maintained to indicate whether the statistics have already 
been calculated by reading the value for the property. They must be 
recalculated when the flag is reset after calling the InvalidateStatistics 
method; this occurs in both the Create constructor and the UpdateTranslation 
method.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.InvalidateStatistics"/>
<link id="TPOFile.Create"/>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
<link id="TTranslationStatistics"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.InvalidateStatistics">
<short>
Resets the internal flag which indicates that translation statistics has been 
calculated for the entries in POItems.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.Statistics"/>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
<link id="TTranslationStatistics"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.FindPoItem">
<short>
Gets the translation entry with the specified identifier value.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFileItem.IdentifierLow"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FindPoItem.Result">
<short>
TPOFileItem with the specified Identifier value, or <b>Nil</b> when not found.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.FindPoItem.Identifier">
<short>
Identifier (msgid) for the translation entry located in the method. The value 
is converted to lowercase and used to find the matching translation entry.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.OriginalToItem">
<short>
Gets the translation entry which has the specified original (untranslated) 
value.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFileItem"/>
<link id="TPOFileItem.Original"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.OriginalToItem.Result">
<short>
TPOFileItem with the specified Original value, or <b>Nil</b> when not found.
</short>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.OriginalToItem.Data">
<short>
Untranslated value for the entry located in the method.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.PoItems">
<short>
Provides indexed access to the translation entries in the class instance.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>POItems</var> is an indexed <var>TPOFileItem</var> property which allows 
access to the translation entries in the class by their ordinal position. 
Index values must be in the range <b>0..Count-1</b>.
</p>
<p>
Values in POItems are created when the ReadPOText method is called to load the 
content of a .po file or stream into the class instance.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFileItem"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="TPOFile.PoItems.Index">
<short>
Ordinal position for the translation entry in the property value.
</short>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Count">
<short>
Number of translation entries in the POItems for the class instance.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Count</var> is a read-only <var>Integer</var> property which contains the 
number of translation entries found in the class. It contains the value from 
the Count property in the list used to store the POItems instances in the 
class.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="TPOFile.POItems"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="TPOFile.Header">
<short>
Contains values for the header section in a .po file.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>Header</var> is a read-only <var>TPOFileItem</var> property which 
contains values read from the header section in the .po file. The header 
section is the first entry in a PO file that has empty string for its message 
Identifier (msgid). It contains meta-information about the content in the 
file, and also how a plural (a line with Plural-Forms) needs to be handled for 
that language.
</p>
<p>
The Translation property in Header is used to store the metadata found in the 
header section for the .po file. For example:
</p>
<code>
"MIME-Version: 1.0\n"
"Content-Type: text/plain; charset=UTF-8\n"
"Content-Transfer-Encoding: 8bit\n"
"X-Generator: ztrans-tool\n"
"Last-Translator: Wiley Coyote\n"
"Language-Team: acmecorpllc.com\n"
"Plural-Forms: nplurals=2; plural=(n != 1);\n"
"Language: de\n"
</code>
<p>
Use of a header section is optional in the .po file. TPOFile includes the 
CreateHeader method to ensure that the Header property is allocated - even 
when the values are not present in the content for the .po file.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="EPOFileError">
<short>
Exception type raised when an error occurs in the UpdatePOFile or 
UpdatePOFileTranslations routines.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="EPOFileError.ResFileName">
<short>
Resource name where the exception was detected.
</short>
</element>
<element name="EPOFileError.POFileName">
<short>
Name for the .po file where the exception occurred.
</short>
</element>

<element name="SystemCharSetIsUTF8">
<short>
Indicates whether the default system character is UTF-8 for the platform.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
The LCL interfaces expect UTF-8 as the default character encoding. If you do 
not use UTF-8, install a proper widestring manager and set this variable to 
<b>False</b>. The default value for the variable is <b>True</b>.
</p>
<p>
Used in the UTF8ToSystemCharSet routine. When set to <b>False</b>, the 
UTF8ToSys routine is called to transcode a native UTF-8 string value to the 
system character set.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="UTF8ToSystemCharSet"/>
</seealso>
</element>

<element name="GetLanguageIDFromLocaleName">
<short>
Gets the language identifier found in the specified locale identifier.
</short>
<descr>
<p>
<var>GetLanguageIDFromLocaleName</var> is a <var>TLanguageID</var> function 
used to get a language identifier for the values in <var>LocaleName</var>. 
LocaleName contains a value which consists of the following:
</p>
<code>
[lang][_region][.codeset][.modifier]
</code>
<dl>
<dt>[lang]</dt>
<dd>Language code (ISO 639-1 or 639-2).</dd>
<dt>[_region]</dt>
<dd>Region (ISO 3166 country code).</dd>
<dt>[.codeset]</dt>
<dd>Code set (optional/currently ignored).</dd>
<dt>[.modifier]</dt>
<dd>Modifier (optional/currently ignored),</dd>
</dl>
<p>
For example:
</p>
<ul>
<li>EN_US</li>
<li>en_GB.UTF-8</li>
<li>de_DE</li>
<li>es_MX.UTF-8</li>
</ul>
<p>
Values are parsed and stored in the corresponding members in the TLanguageID 
return value.
</p>
<p>
GetLanguageIDFromLocaleName is used in the implementation of the GetLanguageID 
routine for platforms other than Windows.
</p>
</descr>
<seealso>
<link id="GetLanguageID"/>
<link id="TLanguageID"/>
</seealso>
</element>
<element name="GetLanguageIDFromLocaleName.Result">
<short>
TLanguageID with the values found in LocaleName.
</short>
</element>
<element name="GetLanguageIDFromLocaleName.LocaleName">
<short>
String with the language, region, and optional code page for a locale.
</short>
</element>

<element name="GetPOFilenameParts">
<short>
Gets the unit name and language used in the specified Filename.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="GetPOFilenameParts.Result">
<short>
<b>True</b> if the .po file exists and the unit name and language were 
extracted in the method.
</short>
</element>
<element name="GetPOFilenameParts.Filename">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="GetPOFilenameParts.UnitName">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="GetPOFilenameParts.Language">
<short/>
</element>

<element name="FindAllTranslatedPoFiles">
<short>
Returns a string list with the fully-qualified path to .po files for the same 
unit as the specified file name.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="FindAllTranslatedPoFiles.Result">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="FindAllTranslatedPoFiles.Filename">
<short/>
</element>

<element name="TranslateUnitResourceStrings">
<short>
Translates resource strings for one unit.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateUnitResourceStrings.Result">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateUnitResourceStrings.ResUnitName">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateUnitResourceStrings.BaseFilename">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateUnitResourceStrings.Lang">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateUnitResourceStrings.FallbackLang">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateUnitResourceStrings.AFilename">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateUnitResourceStrings.po">
<short/>
</element>

<element name="TranslateResourceStrings">
<short>
Translates all resource strings using the specified .po or .pot file.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateResourceStrings.Result">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateResourceStrings.po">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateResourceStrings.AFilename">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateResourceStrings.BaseFilename">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateResourceStrings.Lang">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="TranslateResourceStrings.FallbackLang">
<short/>
</element>

<element name="UTF8ToSystemCharSet">
<short>
Converts the specified UTF-8-encoded string to the character set for the 
system locale.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="UTF8ToSystemCharSet.Result">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="UTF8ToSystemCharSet.s">
<short/>
</element>

<element name="UpdatePoFile">
<short>
Updates a specified .PO template using the list of translations specified.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
<notes><note>How is this used? See: tools/updatepofiles.pas.</note></notes>
</element>
<element name="UpdatePoFile.Result">
<short>
Returns <b>True</b> if the .PO template was modified and stored in the 
routine.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UpdatePoFile.RSTFiles">
<short>
Translations where the template is applied.
</short>
</element>
<element name="UpdatePoFile.POFilename">
<short>
.PO template processed in the routine.
</short>
</element>

<element name="UpdatePoFileTranslations">
<short>
Updates all .po translation files found in the path using the specified .pot 
template file.
</short>
<descr/>
<errors></errors>
<seealso/>
</element>
<element name="UpdatePoFileTranslations.BasePOFilename">
<short/>
</element>
<element name="UpdatePoFileTranslations.BasePOFile">
<short/>
</element>

<element name="sFuzzyFlag">
<short>
Value used for the "fuzzy" flag in a translation entry.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="sBadFormatFlag">
<short>
Value used for the "badformat" flag in a translation entry.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="sFormatFlag">
<short>
Value used for the language-specific "format" flag in a translation entry.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

<element name="sNoFormatFlag">
<short>
Value used for a language-specific "format" flag is not used in a translation 
entry.
</short>
<descr/>
<seealso/>
</element>

</module>
<!-- Translations -->
</package>
</fpdoc-descriptions>
